（柔和的音乐）
-[旁白]斯坦福大学
-[讲师] CS193P 2020年春季。
这是第六讲
今天我要介绍两个简短的主题，
因为他们是次要话题，所以简短
像财产观察员一样
否则我只会深入了解其中的细节
就像@State。
然后我们今天将探讨我们的主要主题，
这是动画，这就是我们的演示
所有关于。
因此，让我们开始吧。
物业观察员对此只作简单介绍。
我想让你明白的主要事情
关于财产观察员，这只是观看变量的一种方法
并查看何时更改，然后采取一些措施。
现在，很多时候人们感到困惑
在属性观察者和计算变量之间。
他们是完全不同的东西，
彼此无关。
在这里，我有这个var isFaceUp
上面有一个属性观察器。
该var存储在内存中，
无论如何它都不是计算的变量。
在财产观察员那里，我正在看
因为何时设置isFaceUp
如果设置了新值，
换句话说，事情会面朝上，
那么例如在这种情况下，
就像在我们的“记忆游戏”中一样
我要开始使用奖金时间，开始小馅饼
我们的表情符号后面开始滴答作响。
如果isFaceUp即将设置为false，
我将停止使用奖励时间。
所以newValue在这里是紫色的东西
那是只出现的特殊变种
在遗嘱中设置在这里。
当然，还有一个didSet
我将在演示中使用它，只是有所不同，
在那个oldValue里面是什么值
在它改变之前。
好了，对于下一个主题，我想解释一下
关于发生的事情并不太明显
我之前还没有真正谈论过
但是您的视图（例如CardView）和EmojiGameView，
它们都是只读的。
换句话说，如果您在顶部查看
以及您设备上的所有SwiftUI，一应俱全。
您可能会认为这是不可能的。
我们如何才能不改变观点
观点一直在变化。
但是我们不是只读的
这意味着拥有存储的var
在我们看来，这是没有用的。
反正我们不能设置它的值
唯一的例外是设置的变量
当你创建
风景。
就像在CardView中，我们有isFaceUp，
它是由创建它的人设置的
因此将其作为变种是有意义的。
但是其他没有这样设置的东西
它可能也是一个让。
或者如果它绝对是计算的var
只想成为一个只读的计算变量，
到目前为止，这是我们唯一的一种计算型var。
为什么？
为什么它们都是只读的？
好吧，函数式编程
一件令人敬畏的事情，
关于可变性很清楚，
什么时候可以更改？
好的设计有很大的溢价
使事情变得一成不变。
当事物是不可变的
没有人在幕后改变它
或做一些破坏可证明性的事情
您的代码实际有效。
而且，当事物是可变的或不可变的时，
当他们改变时，你知道他们在改变，
您可以为此做些事情。
这就是我们可以在上面使用这些属性观察器的方式
价值类型如此有效。
对于SwiftUI，
它想知道事情何时发生变化，
当他们改变的时候，它想做的最少
用正确的视图替换视图层次结构的工作。
实际上，这就是正在发生的事情，
如果isFaceUp
变化，
它制作了一个新的CardView。
这就是所有工作的方式。
这实际上对你来说是一件很棒的事
您可能不这样认为。
您不能拥有读写var的事实真的很好
因为记住你的观点
应该是无国籍的。
他们应该一直在反思
模型的状态是什么。
状态即在模型中。
因此，您不需要自己的任何状态，对吗？
无需将它们设置为只读。
好吧，主要是
并非100％正确。
因此，让我们谈谈Views何时确实需要某种状态。
还有一些罕见的时期
当它确实需要状态时，它总是临时的。
视图从不长期存储
那将永远存在于您的模型中。
这只是暂时的情况
您可能需要一点存储空间的地方。
您可能需要哪些临时存储示例？
好吧，您可能会进入“编辑模式”，
您要从用户那里收集一些数据的地方
并收集起来，然后调用意图更改模型
使用您收集的数据或其他方式。
所以只是暂时的，您正在收集它。
您可能正在显示另一个视图，
其他一些正在收集数据的视图
例如TextField或Picker，
就像我们在广场上的那个帖子中看到的一样
或具有作为警报的视图，
您正在向用户发出警报，
你只是想跟踪它上升的事实
直到用户点击“取消”，
然后您会想，“啊，它不见了”。
因此，您只是个布尔人，
那个事情是否发生
那种很小的临时数据或动画。
动画只反映过去的事物。
因此，如果您想制作某种动画
与当下，
您必须有一个小var，这就是未来。
因此您可以将var设置为将来
动画将开始朝着未来发展。
希望您将未来设定为
最终将是同样的事情
在你的永久状态。
但是你只用那个变量
在动画发生的时间
我们知道动画很短，
他们只是暂时的东西。
动画，这些临时存储的另一种情况，
我们将在演示中看到这样做。
实际上，我们可以在只读视图中创建存储
我们通过标记一个var
使用@State存储我们想要的信息。
所以@State你知道，
像@ Published，@ ObservedObject，
这是一个属性包装器。
请注意，我已将此状态标记为私有。
那是因为国家对你是私人的
这只是您在View中使用的临时存储，
没有其他人会看着它。
因此，将其标记为私有，只是提醒自己，
是的，这是一个私人国家
那里的临时状态。
当然，这个东西的类型可以是任何类型，
您基本上是在这里声明一个变量，
那将是可读写的。
但是它可以是您想要的任何类型。
要了解有关此状态变量的一件重要事情，
如果我更改它，这是暂时的，
我的视图可能会重绘。
如果我的观点是暂时的，
它以某种方式改变，使我的身体变得不同
它会被重画。
和ObservedObject一样，对吗？
我们在ViewModel上观察到对象。
如果ViewModel以某种方式更改
这将使我们的视图看起来与众不同。
将与状态重新绘制相同的东西
这实际上是它的一个很酷的功能。
此@State var的空间
将在堆中分配。
它必须，不能在您的视图中留出空间，
您的视图是只读的
所以基本上是在做一个指针
所以你的视图里面有一个指针
它指向堆。
当您的视图重建时，
导致您的View一直在重建，
当isFaceUp在CardView中更改时，
您必须制作一个新的CardView。
当那件事发生时
该指针移至新版本
所以您仍然指向堆中的同一件事。
因此，如果isFaceUp发生变化，
您的CardView不会丢失其临时存储。
基本上，您的临时存储甚至会保留
以及其他导致您的视图的因素
甚至完全重建
您可以保留@State。
我们将学习这些@符号事物，
你知道@Published @ObservedObject @State
他们被称为属性包装器。
您可以在阅读中阅读有关内容。
我认为是下周分配的。
我最终会在演讲中解释它。
不过，还没有到那儿。
现在，只知道您可以使用@State标记var
现在您可以写了。
但是请谨慎使用，并且绝对不要
放一些不是临时的东西。
好的，当天的主题是动画。
什么是动画？
这本质上是一种平滑的写照
在一段时间内，在您的用户界面中，
顺便说一下，
您的UI中已经发生的更改。
当用户观看动画时，
他们看到的东西已经改变
在模型中，好吧，
或某处已经改变
至少已经更改了@State。
已经发生的事情
它无法用其他任何方式做到。
否则，您模型中的所有变量都将具有
随着动画的进行不断变化
那只是站不住脚的架构，对吗？
所以你的模型改变了
您的视图发生了变化，该变化得到了
动画在用户的眼前。
因此，它向您显示了他们最近的过去。
动画的重点是使用户体验
显然，少一点干涩的
而且要引起人们对事物变化的关注。
我们想利用用户的外围视觉来注意到
哦那边那个数字在变
哦，无论如何，View都移到了这里。
那就是我们使用动画的目的
这就是为什么我们有动画。
这也只会使人更愉快，
少压力的经历
一直在屏幕上跳跃。
那么在SwiftUI中，什么可以动画呢？
好吧，我要说的是什么可以动画
但首先，我想说清楚
该动画仅适用于“视图”
在一个容器里
已经在屏幕上了。
因此，如果它们位于已经在屏幕上的容器中
他们发生了变化，
可以产生什么样的变化？
好吧，Views的出现和消失
仅当它们在容器中时，才在屏幕上显示
还更改了可动画制作的ViewModifiers的参数，
例如不透明度和旋转度
提升ViewModifiers知道如何为自己设置动画。
今天我们要创建自己的一个
对这些参数的更改可以进行动画处理。
以及论点的改变
是形状的创造。
如果您创建形状，
以某种方式配置了某些参数，
然后你改变那些，
然后可以对其进行动画处理以进入新状态。
那么我们如何开始动画呢？
顺便说一下，就是改变了
没有别的可以改变
只是ViewModifiers，Shape，
以及视图的出现和消失，
想说清楚。
好了，那么我们如何制作动画呢？
好吧，有两种方法可以做到。
一个是隐式动画
我们要标记一个视图然后说，
只要此视图上的修饰符之一发生变化，
我们将动画化这一变化。
因此，隐式动画将自动
每当该视图上的修改器发生变化时，
它将对其进行动画处理。
第二个是明确的
我们将在其中调用一些将要产生的代码
在对ViewModifiers或Shapes的一些更改中，
或观点将会来去去去。
我们将包装该代码
通过withAnimation调用此函数。
在花括号里面，
我们要把代码
那会导致所有会改变的事情
所有这些更改的ViewModifier参数，
所有的观点来去去去。
他们都会一起发生
在一个并发动画中。
因此，我们在此处明确设置动画，
我们说的是对此进行动画处理，然后我们通常
做类似在我们的ViewModel中调用Intent的事情。
而且我们知道这将会带来很多改变
我们希望将所有结果一起动画化。
这就是显式动画。
因此，让我们先谈谈隐式动画。
有人称这种自动动画
本质上只是声明或标记一个视图
这样所有的ViewModifier参数
总是动画
对于此视图。
您可以指定这些事情的发生方式，
就像他们发生需要多长时间。
还有我要谈论的曲线
您确实可以控制它。
您可以通过在任何View上调用此函数动画来完成此操作。
所以在这里我称其为不透明度或旋转度
修改后的幽灵文字。
我说过动画，在那里提供了论据，
动画的制作方法
多久，所有的东西。
而且现在永远，只要可怕的变种变化，
因此不透明度发生了变化，
或upsideDown var在那里改变
旋转效果将改变旋转。
每当这些变化发生时，它就会产生动画效果，
因为此“查看此组合”显示为绿色，
现在是隐式动画的。
总是会发生这种情况。
警告这里，小红字警告，请注意
.animation在容器上查看
无法正常使用您通常认为的方式
你可能想像，它会动画
整个容器就像一个大的，某种程度上的变化。
但这并不能全部在容器上做动画，
它只是将动画应用于所有事物
在容器内。
换句话说，.animation与.padding不同，对。
.padding使整个ZStack处于填充状态
或整个VStack或其他任何东西。
它更像.font，或者如果您在ZStack上说.font，
ZStack中的所有文本，获取该字体，好吧。
动画更像.font
如果您在ZStack上说动画，
里面的所有东西都会得到那个，那就是
很少您真正想要的东西令人惊讶。
所以我只是警告你
我们通常不将.animation放在容器视图上，
他们通常戴在叶子视图上，
至少在很小的独立视图上。
这样动画论点
在上一张幻灯片中看到的您正在经过的地方，
这很容易进出，这叫做
使您可以像控制动画持续时间一样控制动画。
这要花多长时间？
两秒钟或任何延迟
请等待半秒钟，然后再开始播放此动画。
它可以重复一定次数，
甚至永远重复
做动画来做这个改变，
然后不断重复制作动画。
当然，过去已经进行了更改，
但只要继续做动画
有时候你想这么做。
您还可以设置动画的曲线。
那么动画曲线是什么？
这实际上是由
您选择哪种动画。
动画曲线控制速率
动画播放时
例如，在线性动画中，
在整个过程中，速率保持恒定
整个动画，从一个不透明度到另一个，
或一次旋转或另一次旋转
发生时，线性恒定速率。
然后这种放松，放松
我在上一个提到的那是不同的。
它开始缓慢，缓慢改变不透明度
旋转，然后加速，
然后几乎快要减速了。
为什么要这样的东西？
好吧，例如，如果您
在屏幕上将卡片从一个地方移动到另一个地方，
如果只是拿起步伐，那是一种突然。
这样做更好
开始缓慢移动，然后移动，然后减速
当它到达时，有点像一架飞机，对。
从跑道停止处开始，然后慢慢起飞
然后飞到空中，时速达到500英里
然后到达目的地机场
然后减速到每小时100到150英里，
然后它降落。
这就是利率的曲线
轻松进出。
您几乎总是希望事情动起来
至少放松一下，放松一下
如果不是下一个，那就是春天。
所以春天才是目的地
然后有点反弹
那里有一点软着陆
稍微超过标记并弹回
有点像弹簧连接它
到目的地。
这些动画曲线使用户界面
给用户带来更多舒适感，更少，
震颤，不那么突然。
所以我们来谈谈隐式动画
当我认为我只是在描述一个明确的动画时，
接下来是我要描述的。
这些自动的，隐式的动画
它们甚至不是我们制作动画的主要方式。
这可能取决于应用程序
但大多数情况下，我们不会使用太多
因为当您拥有一组视图时，
他们想一起做动画。
这就是为什么将.animation放在ZStack等容器上，
不只是，我们只是做得并不多。
因为如果ZStack里面有很多View
也许在那些大建筑物里面的景色，
这些视图要一起动画，
所有相同的持续时间，所有相同的曲线，
他们想保持同步。
显式动画是我们导致动画发生的地方
都具有相同的持续时间，都具有相同的曲线
一堆视图。
而我们要做的就是
withAnimation函数，调用它
这个参数是闭包，
在封闭内部，我们要做一些事情
就像在我们的ViewModel上调用Intent一样，
那是我们在那里做的经典事情。
模型可以疯狂地改变
我们的观点可能会发生疯狂的变化，
所有那些疯狂的改变都会一起发生
与我们传递给withAnimation的动画有关。
在这里，我正在做两秒钟的线性动画。
所以所有的变化都将以线性速率发生
在两秒钟的过程中。
现在，我在这里用Animation调用一个函数
一个有两个参数，一个动画，然后是一个闭包，
调用这样的函数
那更多是一种当务之急的编程方法。
我们知道SwiftUI主要是声明性的，
我们只是说一切的状态
隐式动画是声明性的。
你只是在宣布
当这些东西的这些修饰符改变时，
您将为其设置动画。
但这实际上是必须的。
在这里，我们告诉某人
做这个并制作动画
因此势在必行。
因此，SwiftUI代码中没有很多地方，
您在进行命令式编程的地方。
请记住，所有这些代码都必须在您的视图中，
因为ViewModels看不到View
所以他们不能这样做。
这一切都在您的视野中，
它就在您的SwiftUI代码中，
您在其中执行命令式代码（例如onTapGesture），
点击视图，繁荣，
你要做一些当务之急，
您会说选择意图，选择卡片或其他任何东西。
这些就是发生的事情的地方
就像轻按一样，只是其他手势
我们将在下周学习。
那就是我们要调用动画的时候。
现在，正如我所说，动画是明确的，
通常包裹在Intent之类的东西周围，
一个ViewModel Intent。
但您也可以将其包裹在发生的事情周围
仅在用户界面中。
例如，我正在谈论的编辑模式，
假设您要进入编辑模式
和小图标将出现以删除内容或其他内容
那些东西想要平滑地动画
并出现在屏幕上。
因此，当用户
点击按钮以说进入编辑模式或其他。
另一个必要的地方是按钮的动作。
我今天还将在演示中展示Buttons
然后您会看到Button的动作是另一个地方
我们执行命令式代码，以及在可能的地方
用withAnimation做类似的事情。
这又是红色，第二个红色的东西。
第一个是做事的红色
.animation在容器视图上。
这是提醒您显式动画
不要覆盖隐式动画。
假定隐式动画出现在“视图”上
他们是独立的，他们独立工作，
任何动画对他们来说都有意义
无论如何，对他们总是有意义的。
因此，如果有一个视图，
并且附有一个隐式动画
那就要做那个隐式动画
每当事情改变时。
即使有明确的动画
同时进行。
对他们没有任何影响。
隐式地动画总是赢。
现在过渡指定如何为到达动画
和视图的离开。
记住，这些视图必须放在容器中
已经在屏幕上。
但是无论何时到达，都希望能够对其进行动画处理
从外太空或其他物体中消失或飞入
您想要该View到达的某种动画。
现在是过渡
只是
一对ViewModifiers，仅此而已
ViewModifiers之一正在修改
视图，那里应该是什么样子
另一个正在修改视图的内容
它不存在时应该看起来像。
换句话说，它还没有到达或刚刚离开，
那里的那个可能会有
假设它是一种淡入淡出，它将从一个开始
ViewModifier，它位于不透明度为1的位置，
然后另一个的ViewModifier是不透明度为零。
系统将在这两个ViewModifiers之间进行动画处理
使那个东西出现或消失。
所以过渡实际上只是一个版本
ViewModifier的参数更改
导致过渡的就是这对修饰符。
这两个修饰符可以具有不同的参数
就是这样，仅此而已。
所以过渡不是真的
另一种动画
这只是指定两个ViewModifiers的一种方式
用于何时显示和消失视图。
那么我们如何指定想要的过渡
动画外观时要使用的系统
或给定视图的消失？
记住过渡只是一对修饰符，
所以我们实质上只是要附加两个修饰符
我们想要修改器在屏幕上显示的时间和修改器
当不是视图时
我们使用.transition附加此过渡，
非常简单的ViewModifier。
我在这里以身作则，
我将使用两个内置的过渡。
一个叫做.scale，就是那里的蓝色
另一个称为.identity，即紫色。
因此，.scale过渡
它的两个ViewModifiers是框架修改器。
屏幕外的一帧为零，
屏幕上有一个全尺寸的框架
只要它的正常大小。
因此，比例转换可将View从微小的位置放大和缩小，
零尺寸，最大尺寸为进出时的最大尺寸。
身份转换是一个有趣的过程，
它是ViewModifier不执行任何操作。
因此，既然消失之间没有任何变化，
当它在那里时，它会立即出现
并立即消失。
换句话说，没有动画，因为
两个ViewModifiers之间没有区别
完全一样
他们实际上并没有修改视图
因此没有动画发生。
因此，bloop出现并消失。
有时候是这样
当您制作动画时，
你有来来往往的景观，
也许你可能想要一个视图
只是bloop出现而bloop消失
而不是动画。
这不是默认值
因此默认的过渡称为.opacity，
是淡入淡出，淡入淡出，正确。
这只是不透明
我们上次了解到的
出门时从一变为零
从零到一
所以我们在这种情况下进行了审核
是不透明度ViewModifier。
让我们在这里看看这个ZStack，
基本上是我们的卡片
这里简化。
幻灯片上只有这么多空间，
您可以从正面朝上看到卡片正面，
我得到了RoundedRectangles，
假设没有在此处指定所有内容，
但是你知道它们是什么。
而且我没有放.transition修饰符
在RoundedRectangles上。
因此，他们将获得默认过渡，
这是不透明的。所以前面的RoundedRectangles
当它们来来去去时会淡入淡出。
但是我确实对文本进行了过渡
那里的小鬼。
那将会无处不在
然后在消失时将其缩小为零。
这就是.scale的意思。
然后背面的RoundedRectangle
我将过渡身份表示为
当后面出现时，它会出现斑点
它不会淡入或长出，它会出现斑点。
现在它会出现，同时
正面将逐渐消失，变焦缩小
与此同时。
所以这将不是一个很好的动画。
这是一种厨房水槽动画，
你永远不会这样做
但我只想让你明白
所有这些过渡是做什么的。
顺便说一下，您在这里看到isFaceUp，
这只是ViewBuilder内部的条件，对吗？
这是ZStack，
我们知道ZStack的内容是ViewBuilder。
在ViewBuilder中，它是一个View列表
但是我们可以使用if-thens来包含或不包含某些内容，
好吧，当然，当我们包括它们时，
它们出现在屏幕上，因为我们不包含它们，
他们消失在屏幕上。
以及ViewBuilders中的这些if-thens
可能是第一种方法
意见来来去去。
因此，当您对内容进行动画处理时
一些诸如ZStack之类的ViewBuilder，
里面有条件
您想考虑过渡，
因为那些事情会来来去去
如果你不考虑的话
您将会渐入渐出。
这是默认设置，但您可能需要一些东西
看起来比那更好。
例如，视图来来去去的另一种方式是，
在ForEach中。
因此，ForEach采用了一系列可识别的事物，
并为其制作视图。
好吧，如果该数组发生变化，
就像增加了新的东西，
或某些标识符被拔出，
它会添加新的视图或采用某些视图
它是过去制造出来的。
那些观点将会来去去去。
您肯定会在作业中看到这一点
第三，你要拿卡
通过某些ForEach以某种方式显示在屏幕上
也许在年级之内。
这是一个与众不同的游戏
卡片在您正在做的游戏中来来往往。
记住卡片实际上总是在屏幕上，
即使他们匹配，他们也只是隐藏起来。
他们那里有一个空间
但不必那样。
所以这些可能是第一和第二种方式
视图来去去去：ViewBuilders中的条件事物
以及诸如ForEach之类的在本质上有条件的事情
为您建立景观。
好的，回到屏幕代码。
因此，让我们来看一下，
如果我们将isFaceUp从一件事更改为另一件事，
会发生什么？
因此，如果我们将isFaceUp更改为false，
换句话说，我们想露背，
后面会立刻出现
因为我们说过要转变为身份，
这意味着不要做任何修改。
所以没有动画
所以只是bloop立即出现。
文本将缩小为空，
因为它正在使用比例转换
并且前面的RoundedRectangles会淡出
因为他们没有过渡
因此他们获得了默认的不透明度。
顺便说一下，如果isFaceUp更改为true，
isFaceUp必须在这里进行更改，
在进行显式动画制作时。
如果我们实际上没有动画，
那么这些过渡就没有任何意义，对。
这些过渡不会自己制作动画
他们只是指定要使用的ViewModifiers，
发生动画时。
因此，如果isFaceUp从false更改为true，
现在背部会消失，只是消失了
因为再次，它的过渡
是标识ViewModifier。
因此，标识ViewModifier之间没有区别
当它在那里或不在那里。就是这样
它仍然不在屏幕上，所以它消失了。
文本将从无到有
将从零尺寸开始，然后增长到正常尺寸。
从那以后，前面的RoundedRectangles
没有指定过渡，它们会淡入。
这将同时发生。
现在要考虑的一件事是过渡
与动画不同，过渡不会重新分配
到容器的内容视图。
记住，我告诉过你我们通常不放
容器视图上的隐式动画，
因为它最终只是给那个动画
里面的每一件事。
好吧，过渡并不能做到这一点。
过渡，当您将其放在ZStack或VStack上时
现在正在谈论过渡
当整个ZStack出现在屏幕上时
或关闭屏幕。
因此，它不会将其分发到其内部。
它实际上是在谈论动画
ZStack本身的来龙去脉。
现在Group和ForEach，这些是容器视图
但是由于他们在屏幕上的任何地方都不会放任何东西，
他们实际上只是在分组或创建视图
从可识别列表中，
他们确实将.transition分发到其内容视图。
因此，如果您说一堆东西，
你说.transition，
将会谈论其中的每一件事，
获得过渡。
这个.transition函数
记得除了指定
这两个ViewModifiers是什么。
在那里将单词transition视为一个名词。
这是要使用的过渡。
它不是动词，就像现在的视图过渡一样，
过渡仅在显式动画出现时发生
正在进行。
那是过渡动画唯一发生的时间。
过渡实际上不适用于隐式动画。
如果您尝试制作隐式动画，
在带有过渡的视图上
会有点困惑
而且您可以理解为什么会记住这一点，您知道，
显式动画用于动画
协调了许多不同的观点
当视图来来去去时。
隐式动画是独立的，
独立的工作视图，使它们的动画有意义。
在我看来，这并不像Views来来去去。
过渡不打算使用
带有隐式动画
它们将与显式动画一起使用。
这是过渡动画唯一发生的时间
是在制作动画时。
转换只是说要使用什么ViewModifier，
您仍然必须设置动画。
顺便说一句，如果您在
有过渡的东西，视图就来了，
它会做一些动画，
但这可能不会达到您的期望。
过渡API，
你知道，就像创建一个实际的过渡
有点有趣。
并且已被类型擦除。
这意味着实际的过渡类型
真正的过渡类型将是
不在乎这是两个ViewModifiers
您正在使用的所有内容。
它们可能非常复杂。
我们正在尝试将它们作为.transition的参数传递
我们不想那样，所以我们要简单。
.transition函数的参数
被称为AnyTransition。
而且此AnyTransition是类型擦除的过渡。
想像一下，
那AnyTransition只是一个带有初始化程序的结构
不用理会，
这是我们拥有修饰符和所有其他东西的过渡。
而且它只知道如何使用它进行过渡。
而您得到的只是AnyTransition
没有任何不在乎或任何业务。
如此擦除类型，就可以简化和丢失。
我们并没有真正失去它，
但我们看不到所有细节
就像它使用的是哪种ViewModifiers，
我们在许多情况下都在Swift中做到了，
您甚至可以使用View
有一个名为AnyView的视图，
它的初始化程序将采用任何一种View
不管有多复杂并返回您的AnyView
并删除所有这些信息，
您现在将拥有一个称为AnyView的视图，
它是AnyView类型的
你对里面的东西一无所知
或修改过的内容，或全部都没有。
如果你不明白我在说什么
关于类型擦除，不必太担心
我们将在本季度晚些时候再次看到它。
但重要的是要意识到
那AnyTransition只是一个结构。
它具有一些用于内置过渡的静态var
就像不透明，它可以动画化不透明度，
为框架修改器设置动画的比例
使帧降为零然后返回。
您的作业有一个非常重要的过渡
叫做offset CGSize，
这会导致视图在屏幕上移动
在它来去去时有一些偏移。
好吧，在你的家庭作业中
使您的卡片被处理
从屏幕外飞到屏幕上
所以您将要使用此偏移过渡
对于那些意见。
您当然可以创建自己的过渡
通过仅指定两个ViewModifiers。
屏幕上有东西时使用的修饰符
并在不正确的时候使用，对，所以
身份是开启时的状态，而活跃时则是活动的状态。
您还可以覆盖使用的动画
如果您一直想要过渡，请进行过渡
例如，要快或慢。
您可以使用此.animation
您对过渡的重视，好吧，
您知道吗，像.animation一样附加它。
不要被这个小东西弄糊涂
这不是隐式动画，
隐式动画过渡，它们不能一起使用。
这只是覆盖持续时间的一种方法
和曲线以及所有过渡动画
这样总是这样。
过渡可能很棘手，并且有些令人沮丧
有时候，当您第一次使用它们时，
因为这个限制
具有视图的屏幕必须已经在屏幕上。
例如，在您的家庭作业三中，
您需要以动画方式分发卡片
时尚到屏幕上。不能像在哪里记忆
记住发射，哦，
屏幕上已经有卡片了。
不，必须暂时启动
然后卡片飞起来并自动运行，
屏幕上会出现一种交易动画。
你如何摆脱这个难题
包含卡片的视图必须首先出现在屏幕上
然后在屏幕上显示之后
那么您可以做一些导致卡片发生的事情。
View有一个很棒的功能可以帮助您
叫做onAppear，非常简单。
有点像onTapGesture，对，
onTapGesture，在发生轻按时会调用此闭包，
执行一些代码，这是一样的，
当视图出现在屏幕上时，它将调用此代码。
所以我们将使用这个不错的小功能
在我们的容器视图上。
在容器视图上，我们将添加onAppear
在该代码中，我们将进行更改
我们模型中的某些东西可能使它
所以那些不存在的卡，
当我的容器视图首次出现时，
关于他们的一些改变
现在他们需要在那里。
现在，他们将在屏幕上播放动画。
我们正在使用这样的事实，我们知道您在Appear上知道
我们的容器视图终于出现在屏幕上了
继续对模型做一些意图，说，好吧，
您可以立即发卡。
因此，模型必须以某种方式更改
现在突然被扔进了视野，
因为视图只是反映了模型中的内容。
因此，如果模型说卡片在那里，
当应用启动时，它们将在那里。
因此，在应用启动时，卡片不必在那儿，
然后在容器上发生onAppear之后，
然后卡片在那里的地方发生了一些事情。
所以您已经得到了信息，我敢肯定，
实际的动画是由ViewModifiers完成的
和形状。
它们是真正活跃的东西。
他们如何参与整个动画系统？
ViewModifiers和Shapes，如何动画化？
好吧，本质上，
动画系统将持续时间分开
动画分成小块，
取决于曲线。
然后它只询问所有形状和ViewModifiers
可以动画的
在这里，画这幅画，画这幅画，画这幅画，对，
只是一遍又一遍地吸引他们
然后将其拼凑成小电影，
这是动画。
而已。
这件事就是这样
要使它正常工作，它是非常优雅和简单的。
动画系统之间的通讯
而ViewModifiers和Shapes只是一个变量，
此var animatableData。
这个animatableData在Animatable协议中，
这是那里唯一的变种。
您所要做的就是实现这一点。
如果您是Shape或ViewModifier，
您可以参加这个分段动画。
animatableData的类型是无关紧要的。
其实有点关怀
因为该类型必须实现协议
VectorArithmetic，这很有意义
因为我们要使用这个animableData，
无论是角度的旋转
派的东西，或者类似的东西
我们将切成小块
所以我们必须能够对此做一些数学运算
用那条漂亮的曲线把它切成碎片
所以类型几乎总是浮点数
很多时候是浮动的，两倍的或CGFloat的
因为我们正在这里做很多绘图。
但是还有另一个实现VectorArithmetic的结构
叫做AnimatablePair真的很酷。
它将两个VectorArithmetic事物组合为一个
动画VectorArithmetic事物。
当然，您可以拥有AnimatablePairs
AnimatablePairs。
因此，您可以拥有任意数量的动画对象。
另外，如果您有自己的复杂结构，
封装了动画数据，
您可以使其实现VectorArithmetic，
那只是一个协议。
它可以直接制作动画。
animatableData只能是某种东西
可以切成小块。
因此，它必须实现VectorArithmetic。
正如我所说，这个变种正在双向交流
动画系统之间
以及Shapes和ViewModifiers。
因此，此var的设置
那就是动画系统说的
这是一小块，画出来，
所以基本上是在说曲线中的哪个位置
你的一些动画数据是
在这个动画中。
现在，获取var也对
动画系统知道动画的开始和结束。
现在，这个animableData
通常是计算型变数，不是因为必须
绝对不是必须的。
就像我们在Pie中的代码一样，
或者您知道我们的Cardify ViewModifier，
我们将对其进行修改，以便卡片翻转
它旋转了。
所以在那边，我真的很想称呼轮换
我的翻转卡“旋转”
我不想称它为animatableData，
它不是var的好名字。
所以很多时候我们要创建一个计算变量
只是本质上重命名一些内部变量
这样动画系统才能看到它。
因此，让我们开始进行演示。
我们将在这里做很多动画工作。
我们将做隐式动画，
但显然是做明确的动画
我们要过渡
我们将要修改一个ViewModifier，
我们将修改Shape的所有内容，
这是一个很大的，很长的演示。
因此，让我们现在就深入研究它。
让我们从这里开始动画演示
带有一些隐式动画。
再次，这是一个动画，我们将要
有一些非常独立的动画
无论如何，它总是适用。
它并没有真正与许多其他活动协调
在动画系统中进行。
为此我们要做的是拥有表情符号
真的很兴奋并庆祝
当他们通过翻筋斗来比赛时。
所以翻筋斗实际上是在旋转
周围的表情符号。
旋转真的很容易
在SwiftUI中，有一个ViewModifier
因为它称为旋转效果。
所以我要去这里查看我的文字，这是我的表情符号，
我只是要添加旋转效果
在上面。
它需要一个角度，所以我要做角度。
我们在做Pie时就知道了这一点。
我要说的是，如果卡片匹配，
然后让我们开始颠倒一下，
180度旋转
我们最终将不得不进行完全的翻筋斗
一路走来
并运行。
点击卡片，我们正在寻找比赛。
哦，是的，它倒过来了
但在那里没有做任何形式的动画。
就和bloop匹配了
他们颠倒了。
那么我们该如何制作动画呢？
好吧，假设我一直想翻筋斗
当卡片匹配时，
我要做的就是在这里隐式动画
并说动画。
我只指定动画的参数。
所以我要让这个动画是线性的
我们将持续一秒钟。
我们在讲座中谈到的这个动画对象
这绝对是您想要的
查看此处的开发人员文档，
我们可以看到所有不同种类的动画
easeIn，easyInOut，线性等所有其他内容。
我说我们可以做：延迟动画，
显然会创建具有一定持续时间的内容。
这是所有需要学习的温泉
关于动画。
今天我们将做很多这样的事情。
因此，让我们尝试一下，看看是否可行。
现在，这会在一秒钟内实现吗，
这是一个，哦，哇，
好吧，其中一个动画在这里，而不是两个。
让我们尝试另一个。
但同样，它会在一秒钟内完成该动画
做到这一点，但它没有做到这一点。
现在，事实是，它仅执行其中一项操作，
有一个很好的理由
我们稍后再讲。
现在，让我们确定一个正在运行的
在做我们想要的。
让我们说360
所以一直。
我们正在尝试找到一个匹配的配对，
喔，一直到处翻筋斗。
这些家伙呢？
喔，也许一旦配对，我们很兴奋
我们只是想继续前进或翻筋斗。
让我们来看看这里的动画
这个线性动画，让我们重复RepeatForever。
所以它正在做相同的动画
只是现在它会继续前进。
现在的事情是，注意它确实做到了
但是它有点逆转
然后它再次执行并反转自身。
这真的不是我们想要的
我们想四处走走。
幸运的是，repeatForever在这里有一个争论，
这是自动反转，我们会说自动反转为假，
我们不希望它扭转
我们只想不断重复播放该动画。
那是因为这个动画返回
到它开始的地方，所以很有意义
不断做下去。
关于这个动画的唯一一件事
想在这里稍微小心一点的是
最终我们要添加一个新游戏
你在家庭作业中所做的
当我们这样做时，这些视图将被重用。
而且我们不希望这个动画开始
在一个新游戏中。
因此，从本质上讲，只要卡不匹配，
我们不想永远重复一次。
因此，无论何时您进行重复的永久动画，
您要小心将其关闭
当它不再适用时。
您只需说出卡片是否匹配即可在此处进行操作。
我们将永远重复这一过程。
但是否则，我们要回去做
不管默认动画是什么。
就像别再做这个动画了。
确保没有破坏任何东西。
我们去比赛了。
Who，它在工作
它正在工作。
现在，我们完成了此隐式动画。
让我们继续做一个明确的动画。
在做显式动画之前，
我将执行您所做的一些工作
特别是在您的作业中，
我要实施洗牌
而且我还要实施新游戏。
洗牌，
这是一个简单的到这里的模型
当我们创建卡片时，
我只是说cards.shuffle。
显然，如果您还没有做完一项作业，
希望您不会观看此视频。
但是接下来我要做新游戏
我们在那里有新游戏，这是第二本作业。
希望您已经完成了第二个作业，
这是在本次讲座之前。
但是如果您还没有完成两个作业，
现在该暂停该视频了，
去提交你的作业二，然后回来
并继续观看。
因此，使用cards.shuffle可以修复好那根衬纸。
喔，这两个东西现在都洗了
彼此相邻。
好吧，我们仍然可以匹配它们。
好吧，新游戏怎么样？
新游戏要求我们在ViewModel中有一个Intent，
就像我们有选择卡片的意图一样，
我们将需要一个意图来创建一个新游戏。
所以我叫这个resetGame
我将通过创建一个新模型来重置游戏
我会说Model = EmojiMemoryGame.createMemoryGame
创建新的记忆游戏，
这就是我要做的。
显然这将改变模型
这将导致这个ObservableObject
因为此模型是@Published，
所有这些都会发生，我们的整体视图将会重绘
因为这种变化。
所以现在我需要在用户界面的某个位置添加一个按钮，对吗？
在我的界面中，我实际上没有新的游戏按钮，
我无法让新游戏出现。
因此，我将在底部非常简单的方法中添加一个新按钮。
我要把我的纸牌放在这里
在VStack中
与
一个按钮。
我们没有谈论巴顿
我没想到你在第二作业中
一定要做一个按钮，
您可以轻松完成文本
在那儿使用onTapGesture可以了。
但是当我们在这里时，让我们继续
并了解有关Button的知识。
按钮很简单
它只有一个动作，需要执行一些关闭操作
当按钮被按下时。
然后有这个标签
实际上，这就是您要成为标签的任何视图。
所以我要在这里贴上文字标签
上面写着“新游戏”。
就我将要采取的行动而言，
让我们双击那里。
我要执行刚才提到的Intent。
所以self.viewModel.resetgame。
通常，当用户界面发生问题时，
就像我们点击卡片或单击按钮一样，
我们要去做
两种意图
否则我们将要做一些完全
只影响用户界面，只是以某种方式调整用户界面
它并不会真正影响我们模型中的内容。
让我们看看我们的新游戏Button是否有效。
我们单击此处运行，嗯，下面有我们的新游戏
然后我们单击。
让我们看看它在做什么。
我们在那里有了新游戏。
哇，是的，它确实改组了他们，在那里放了新卡。
好吧，让我们看看是否有一些卡匹配
然后把它们放回去。
因此，我们的新游戏Button正常运行。
顺便说一句，这里使用Button和有什么区别
和带有onTapGesture的文本？
好吧，Button很强大，它知道这是一个Button。
因此，由于它出现在不同的平台上，
也许是Apple TV或Apple Watch等等
它会以某种方式绘制此按钮
在那个平台上有意义。
尽管我们使用onTapGesture进行文本处理，
它总是看起来像一段文字
我们点击。
所以我们总是想用一个按钮来实现
当我们做一个按钮。
我们不想做一个文本onTapGesture解决方案。
我想提及的另一件事，就是我们在这里
是这个红色的“ New Game”字符串。
这些琴弦是红色的，我很高兴它们是红色的。
红色通常表示我会注意并且确实
您确实要注意红色的弦，
如果您有红色的弦将出现
在用户面前，您需要做一些工作，
我们现在不讨论
使它们国际化。
这样你可以说
法语，中文或阿拉伯文的新游戏
或任何必须解决的问题。
因此，我们不再谈论这个，
如果您对此有兴趣，
也许通过查看开始文档
在称为localizedString键的位置。
那是至少获得你的弦乐的一种方法
开始本地化。
还有其他地方也需要本地化
像日期之类的东西，日期出现的方式有所不同。
再说一次，我们没有时间谈论这个。
今天我们在谈论动画。
我只想提个提要，那就是事情，
我们最终要小心的地方
关于我们放在这里的字符串。
好吧，新游戏成功了
但是正如我们在这里看到的那样，它没有激活动画，
这样做，哇，它马上就变了。
没有动画。
所以我们希望整个过程都充满生气，
事实证明，这确实很容易
使用显式动画，
我们将包装这个重置游戏，它产生了很大的影响
在我们的模型上，并更改了所有卡片。
好吧，所有这些更改，我们都可以制作动画
在此处用animation编写了简单的一行代码。
就像我们做隐式动画一样，
我们将指定所需的动画。
我要使用easyInOut。注意我没有打字
完整的动画点easeInOut，Swift可以推断出
这是withAnimation的明显论点。
然后需要一个闭包，不带参数，
不返回任何参数，
您可以在此处放置任何所需的代码。
无论这对我们的用户界面造成了什么影响
它会变得生动起来。
让我们看看这样做的样子。
喔，我的天哪，实际上是一大堆
那里的动画效果很好。
现在，如果我们想看看这里到底发生了什么
因为那里还有其他东西
持续褪色
我们可以通过easyInOut来更改持续时间
持续时间的动画，例如，
两三秒。
我会放慢动画的速度，
我总是建议这样做
当你做动画的时候是放慢脚步
看看发生了什么。
因此，我们开始尝试新游戏。
好吧，看到卡片逐渐消失，朝下，
他们就搬到了新位置。
这就是动画。
那么为什么会这样呢？
这些东西正在消失，
那个幽灵，看到他淡出，回到他的卡背上？
那是因为我告诉你
那过渡
默认情况下
不透明。
当我们切换时发生了什么
它正在过渡到新的视图
所以我们只是在淡化新的
并将旧的褪色。
我们真的不想要那个，我们想要我们的卡片
他们走时实际上要翻身
从后到前，从前到后，
我们将在几分钟后解决此问题。
但首先，让我们使用显式动画的相同功能
为此，请点击卡片上的动画，
因为现在非常突然
如果您点击卡片，事情就会立即出现
这样不好
同样，在这里我们选择卡片
从我们可以用动画说的命令性代码中
让我们继续前进，使其成为线性动画
而且我们会尽可能长，这样我们才能真正
看到它的实际效果，看看发生了什么。
在内部，我们会做我们将要做的一切，
那会导致很多变化发生
所有这些更改都将被动画化。
好的，我们去点击
我们可以看到我们正在逐渐淡出
当我们选择一张卡时。
并请注意，我点击了这张卡片，但它动画了
发生的所有变化，包括
这些其他卡片朝下翻转。
这样，当您放置此显式动画时，
它将使发生的一切都充满生气
做在那里的事的结果。
包括类似比赛的内容
让我们尝试在这里找到自己的比赛。
我们不是很擅长这款游戏。
让我们看看，有一场比赛。
顺便说一下，我们在那里获得了隐式动画
如果我们点击此处的另一张卡片，
这两张卡将消失。
让我们看看它们消失的方式，对吗？
因为这是默认过渡
我们尚未指定任何转换
我们得到淡入和淡出过渡
在这里的所有地方。
如果我们希望那些东西消失
成为更酷的动画
像我们如何让它们缩小并消失？
真的很容易再做一次，我们要去这里
找到那个视图，那个视图在哪里？
就在这里
这是View，这是ZStack的名称，
当它面朝上时才存在
或者卡不匹配。
因此，一旦卡片匹配且没有面朝上，
此视图消失。
它过渡出来，好了，从视图中消失了，
所以我们可以在这里说过渡
并选择例如AnyTransition.scale。
因此规模是使用框架制造事物的尺度
放大，缩小到虚无或从无到有。
因此，让我们看看是否可以在这里找到另一个匹配项。
现在，很难做，因为
这里的动画太慢了
哦，有比赛。
好吧，当我们点击其他东西时，
让我们来看看如何为这些汽车的消失制作动画。
哇，现在注意，只有缩小后它们才会消失，
但所有其他动画，包括该隐式动画，
他们继续前进。
关于SwiftUI，您要了解的一件事是
所有动画都可以同时发生
他们都在一起工作。
确实，这是SwiftUI最好的东西之一，
是如何处理所有交互的
动画同时发生。
现在在您的作业中，您将收到卡片
以及进行。
但是你不会让他们缩小规模，
您将要让您的卡在屏幕上飞行。
因此它们将飞离屏幕而不是屏幕，
你知道，缩小。
当它们被处理后，当它们出现在屏幕上时，
他们会飞进去，不会去
具有很好的收缩效果。
并添加该过渡
对于这些来来往往的事情，
还可以使它们回来时，您单击
在新游戏上，它们又回来了，应该放大。
这个AnyTransition和记住的是
该类型删除的过渡版本。
因此，让我们在开发人员文档中进行研究
真的很快，这里是AnyTransition。
这就是我们谈论的身份，不透明性
这是默认的，缩放，滑动，向下滑动到侧面，
这边是偏移量
这是使视图飞来飞去的一种
进进出出。
因此，这可能就是您要做家庭作业的目的。
这是修饰符，您可以在其中指定两个
ViewModifiers。顺便说一下，这种不对称性使您可以
可以让卡片带有一个动画
然后根据需要消失，并显示另一个动画。
看到AnyTransition在这里说，
这是一种类型擦除的过渡。
这种类型擦除是使
这一切都非常简单。
这是这些东西的回报类型
不是过渡角括号的ViewModifier
抵消...这只是AnyTransition。
再说一次，我们将更多地讨论类型擦除
在本季度晚些时候。
现在您可以忽略它
并认为过渡只是哦过渡
不用担心所有的不在乎
和其他可能涉及的东西
具有非类型擦除的过渡。
所以这里的房间动画里的大象，
我们没有的是卡片翻转。
真的，当我们玩纸牌游戏时，
当我们点击这些卡片时，
你不希望他们像这样淡入淡出
我们希望他们翻身。
这就是纸牌的作用，它们会翻转。
那么我们该怎么做翻转动画呢？
好吧，斯威夫特将对我们有很大帮助
因为它有一个Animatable ViewModifier
称为旋转3D效果
就像我们旋转比赛一样旋转它。
如果您还记得，在比赛中，我们以2D旋转，
本质上是一圈又一圈。
我们也可以3D旋转让此View旋转
在围绕不同轴的3D中，
这个y垂直轴，而不是围绕旋转
该点的轴线直指我们。
因此，让我们对该卡进行3D旋转
然后看看它是否有效。
这就是所谓的rotation3DEffect。
然后指定要旋转卡的数量。
再次，在这里，我们将做Angle.degrees。
如果卡面朝上，
那么就不要让它旋转正常
但是如果它面朝下，让我们将其旋转180度。
让我们将其完全翻转。
现在，由于这是3D旋转，所以该轴
该轴表示您要围绕哪个轴旋转，
这是三个数字
因此，例如（0，0，1）将是2D旋转，
原因1，最后一个是z轴。
那是从屏幕上指向你的那个，
而我们想要的是y轴
y轴是垂直轴，
从屏幕顶部开始的那个
一直到屏幕底部
我们希望这种旋转围绕该轴发生。
看看有什么用，那是不对的。
让我们看看我们得到了什么。
哇，哇
所以这很有趣。
它在旋转，
但是视图在那里出现和消失
褪色仍在发生
那真的不是我们想要的。
当我们第一次点击该卡片时，
如果前后都可见
一个人逐渐消失，然后逐渐消失，
背面完全淡出，正面已经淡入。
这很近，很近，
我们正在努力完成这项工作，
但这不是很正确。
因此，有两种方法可以使我完成这项工作。
第一，我们可以有自己的自定义过渡，
正在过渡的过渡
在前后之间
后面有点像我们将它向上翻转，
背面显示
一会儿，直到它站起来
然后它消失了
然后当正面出现时，
它从边缘开始，然后向下旋转。
我们绝对可以编写一个做到这一点的ViewModifier
然后从中过渡出来
或者我们正在使用这种半翻转的方式
让卡进出。
确实有点复杂，
比我认为我们需要做的
因为如果我们还记得动画是如何工作的
我们知道ViewModifiers是主要的东西
做动画。
那为什么不随便拿我们的ViewModifier
这张卡并使其旋转时变得很聪明
本身，这样它只显示前半部分的前部
动画，仅在下半场显示背面。
换句话说，我们将在这里进行Cardify。
这是我们的Cardify
当它旋转时
我们会做到的，这样您就可以旋转自己。
这样做的时候
它将协调旋转时面朝上的内容。
轮换的前半部分
脸朝下将是他们的下半部分旋转，脸朝下。
好吧，我们要做的第一件事就是吃这个
rotation3DEffect在这里
并将其移入
我们的
修饰符。
所以如果我们把它放在这里
并将这个ZStack旋转到这里。
不用旋转卡
在0到180之间的二进制意义上，
我们希望能够控制
整个旋转
因为在上半年，我们只想露出脸
下半场，我们只想朝下展示。
所以我们要在这里更改ViewModifier，
其中涉及的主要变量是旋转。
所以我要轮换
我要成为双打，这将成为
我的度数旋转很简单。
如果我要跟踪旋转并为其设置动画，
然后isFaceUp真的变成了
旋转的函数
如果旋转小于90度
我旋转了180度
则该卡面朝上，否则面朝下
因此，现在我将旋转和面朝上朝下联系在一起。
然后当我有这个rotation3DEffect时
卡isFaceUp控制旋转的过程，
让我们进行实际的旋转。
无论我们将此修改器设置为哪种旋转，
那将是旋转，它将被选中
右脸，正面或不正面，旋转
我仍然希望能够有一个init
那就是isFaceUp。
但是现在当我这样做时
那只是将我的旋转设置为零
如果是正面朝上，如果是正面朝下，则为180，
假设isFaceUp问号为零，否则为180。
所以我在这里转换了ViewModifier
以轮换为基础，而不是面朝上
并且正面朝上总是跟踪旋转
因为这是FaceUp它的
只是看旋转，看看我们是否旋转足够。
现在我们如何制作动画
因为这还不足以使其具有动画效果
如果我们不在这里跑
然后点击这些东西。
它在做翻转，但仍然做错了事
关于面朝上和面朝下。
当正面朝上和正面朝下的视图在此处来回移动时，
他们仍然只是不透明。
那是因为这个ViewModifier
未标记为可动画。
因此SwiftUI认为，这个ViewModifier
不知道如何制作动画。
所以我只是在这里做普通的动画。
我通常会为它设置动画
通过此处的init来彼此初始化。
我只是考虑即将到来的这些观点
因为isFaceUp而去
而我只是在过渡他们
使用标准转换，即不透明度。
所以我们可以打开一个ViewModifier
通过更改协议进入Animatable修改器
实现到AnimatableModifier。
所以Animatable修饰符实际上只是ViewModifier
可动画的，这是可动画的
如果我们查找它，这个animatableData变量，
动画系统之间的这种通信
以及我们的ViewModifier或Shape。
所以我们只需要实现这个animatableData
animatableData放在这里，让我们开始吧。
让我们将其放在此处，var animatableData。
我们的ViewModifier会动画显示什么？
动画旋转
我们的视图就是您要设置的动画。
所以这个Double是我们的轮换。
现在，我可以使用这个单词animatableData
在这里而不是旋转
但这不是在此处具有animatableData的很好的代码。
所以让我们做我在说的那个把戏
在我要放的幻灯片上
这是一个计算属性
我要归还我的轮换
然后我将轮换设为相等
此属性的新值。
记住，获取并设置，这就是我们要做的
计算属性就是读写的。
所以我基本上只是将旋转重命名为animatableData
因为这是动画系统的名称
要寻找。
顺便说一句，即使这只是全部，您也无法
发生在这里，
你实际上不能只说这个
您需要说这是一个AnimatableModifier
因为这个AnimatableModifier协议
虽然这和ViewModifier在一起，
它也向系统发出信号
我想参加，我将成为ViewModifier
想参加动画系统的人
因此请确保您说的是冒号AnimatableModifier。
好吧，让我们尝试一下。
轻按该卡，哦，天哪，
真的很简单。
在翻转的前半部分看到
当卡片正面朝下时，
它只显示背面，当它面朝上时，
它只显示正面，让我们尝试
并使卡消失
这样您就可以看到卡片面朝下。
这是一场比赛，让它消失。
并注意当它消失时仍然可以使用
动画效果就好于缩放动画。
还要注意，当我们翻转卡片时，
不再有淡入。
这些卡不褪色，背面或正面不褪色。
那是因为这个ViewModifier
已经控制了动画。
因此动画系统不再尝试
进入这里并自己制作动画
假定此ViewModifier知道它在做什么。
让我们回到一开始就遇到的问题，
这是当事物匹配时，让我们找到一些卡片
在这里匹配。
现在我又不太擅长这款游戏。
好吧，我认为这是。是的，好的，准备好了，我们开始比赛了。
这一个旋转。
这一个不旋转。
让我们调查一下为什么不旋转？
这不会旋转，因为当我们触摸此卡时，
它匹配并且当时被朝下
我们将其切换为正面朝上。
因此，当它出现在屏幕上时，所有这些融合都在这里，
它面朝上并且已经匹配。
所以没有变化
此卡isMatched已经是真实的
因此无需进行任何更改。
动画仅动画更改。
所以没有变化
导致“视图”出现在屏幕上匹配，
它永远不会改变以匹配
它刚匹配时就匹配了。
所以如果我们想要一场比赛
要跟空翻一起动画
我们需要这张卡，这个文本，
基本上是卡的正面，需要在屏幕上
当比赛发生时。
但这是一张卡的问题，
比赛中的第二张牌，因为它面朝下。
让表情符号位于卡片的正面
它不在屏幕上，但我们仍然可以在屏幕上显示它，
但隐藏起来，这是另一种应对方式
与正在出现和消失的视图
而不是让它们实际上是-如果-然后-从
存在。相反，我们可以将它们隐藏起来。
而我们隐藏事物的方式就是
从上次我们已经知道不透明
完全透明被隐藏
并且完全不透明在屏幕上完全可见。
因此，让我们使用不透明度来获得前后
我们的卡片是否显示，
而不是如果
使它们完全消失或没有消失。
所以这是一种不同的思考方式
ZStack中发生了什么。
而不是随着这些前视图的来临而思考
当它面朝上时
然后当面朝下时他们走了
当它面朝下时就来了，面朝上了。
相反，我将总是拥有所有这四个
卡上。
当它面朝下时
我看不到这三个。
因此，让我们采用这三个，
我什至会把它们分组以使自己更轻松。
然后设置它们的不透明度，以便如果卡片朝上，
他们是完全不透明的
否则它们是完全透明的。
而且这个同样会说它的不透明性
如果面朝上，则完全透明。
否则，基于此，
移动这些东西，使它们更容易阅读
所以现在在这里，如果没有，
这个ViewBuilder内部没有ifs
意见不再来去去了。
这也意味着该内容，
此文本始终显示在屏幕上
即使我们面朝下，也只是隐藏起来。
因此，这意味着当它稍后设置为匹配时，
这种隐式动画将有所改变
直到它开始运行。
让我们尝试一下。
这是我们的卡片，哎呀，在那儿仍然可以正常使用，
卡的正面没有显示
看到卡的正面就在那里
在这张卡的另一面
如果你想这样想
尽管它是隐藏的，但其不透明度为零。
当我单击它时，它的不透明度仍为零
现在它的不透明度是
背面的不透明度设为零。
因此，希望我们能在这里找到比赛的地方，
这家伙
和这个家伙，他们都会旋转
您会看到该卡转过身时正在旋转。
让我们在这里再配一个
看着卡片转过身来
你会看到它已经旋转了
因为它在那里藏着，正在旋转，
隐藏直到它变得可见。
使用不透明度使事情来去去来的技巧
这实际上是您可以控制自己是否在做的一种方式
随Views转换而来的动画，
还是直接在屏幕上进行控制
使用不透明度。
而且它们都是完全有效的方法。
您可以决定是否有意义
在本演示的稍后部分，您将看到
我们实际上将要利用
使我们的小馅饼来来去去。
当我们的派动画时，
我们希望它在那里有动画效果，
但是我们要放一个不同的派
如果不是，那将是一个巨大的优势
知道什么时候来来去去。
因此，并非总是要使用不透明度
有时您想要视图来去去，
这仅取决于您是否触发了此事
以及您是否要使用过渡，
或只是普通动画。
现在我要做的最后一件事是，
现在我们有了动画，
可以很好地翻转卡片
为了让它们消失，
我将再次加速它们
然后我们去制作动画
这个小馅饼。
因此，让我们加快备份速度，这很容易做到。
回到这里，继续努力
也许我们有默认的持续时间，
让我们尝试这两者的默认持续时间，
通常是默认时间的一秒以内。
看看这是什么样子
嗯，实际上可能有点快，
我对此不满意
我很快就消失了
但是当我翻转卡片时我想放慢速度
一点点。
所以我要说持续时间
假设0.75，
看看效果如何。
好吧，对我来说看起来更好
当然不会比这更慢
但我认为这看起来不错。
这种蓝色显然是某种东西
我们想放下我们的绘图常数。
我现在不打算这样做以节省时间
但是只要您看到那里有一个蓝色数字，
这些蓝色的数字也是我们上次没有做的
这些东西都应该放在这里
在绘图常量中，您可以使用控制面板
在这里进行调整并转动拨盘
使您的用户界面看起来像您想要的那样。
我们有这个派
现在Pie被卡在这个位置上
但实际上，每当卡片翻转时，
我们希望它开始倒计时
当它向下翻转时，
我们停止计数，然后再向上推。
它一直计数然后向下翻转
它停止计数，然后当然
当它匹配时，我们停止计数
因为现在您已经匹配了它。
如果它完全消失，
你得的积分不及你做的多
在它消失之前。
为此，我们需要做一些事情。
一个是我们将不得不改进我们的模型
知道还剩下多少奖金时间，等等。
所以我实际上放了一些代码
在这里，我向你们提供了
在之前的论坛上，所以你们所有人都拥有它。
如果没有，您可以暂停该视频
并从这里复制它
以其他方式获得它。
但是这段代码基本上是在做跟踪
每当卡上下时
或被映射它跟踪使用的时间
然后它回答诸如
还剩多少时间
或剩余的时间百分比
我们可以了解我们是否获得奖金
并开始使用奖励时间
并停止使用奖励时间。
通过这些功能，我要确保
当卡片正面朝上和正面朝下时，我称这些为
在我的模型中以及匹配时。
因此，让我们使用我们讨论过的那些财产观察员
调用这些功能。
这是我的
卡的vars。
我要做到，每次
isFaceUp在这里更改了，
我将使用幻灯片中显示的willSet的didSet，
但我只是在这里与众不同
并向您显示didSet。
当这种情况发生时，我要说
如果isFaceUp更改为true。
因此，卡面朝上
然后我将开始再次运行奖金时间，
开始使用奖励时间。
否则，如果卡面朝下，
我将停止使用奖励时间。
所以我只是在我的卡片上看着这个面朝上和面朝下
每当它发生变化时，
这比尝试更可靠
一直看我说isFaceUp是对还是错
然后尝试同时调用startUsingBonusTime
我可能会犯一个错误，却忘记了它。
这样，每次我更改此设置时，它都是可靠的
繁荣我们开始和停止的时间。
同样，对于isMatched在这里，
当didSet时，我们可以停止使用奖励时间。
如果isMatched设置为false，则可能
也许我们正在重置游戏或重置卡片，
不知道我们在那做什么。
但似乎是奖金时间
不应该再开始了。
该属性观察器，一种非常强大的同步方式
您的代码内部发生了什么。
所以现在我们的模型知道还剩多少时间
在奖金和所有这些东西上。
这就是我在这里所做的所有代码。
因此，让我们使用这些东西
在我们的用户界面中显示该动画。
现在让我们的卡片派动画
我们必须在此处增强Shape的动画效果。
现在形状真的已经有了这个Animatable，
与ViewModifier使用的协议相同，
在所有形状上都差不多
假定所有形状都可以动画
这只是形状的一部分。
这种情况太普遍了，我们甚至不必说
逗号可在此处动画化，
形状只是假设您要这样做。
现在，如果您不放置animatableData，
你不会得到任何动画
但是通常我们想要它。
所以我们要在这里制作动画
在我们的Cardify ViewModifier中，
我们四处走动时动画旋转，
好吧，在我们的Pie动画中，
我们有点想动画化这个角度，
看到这里的角度，
当它绕这个角度变化时
此处的结束角度。
如果我们要成为一个好馅饼，
让我们使两个角度都可以动画
开始和结束。
这样我们就可以为任何一侧设置动画，
取决于我们认为看起来不错。
因此，基本上我该如何同时为两件事设置动画
我要用那个AnimatablePair，
对。
而AnimatablePair将是一对Doubles，
那些双打将成为我的视角
他们以弧度为单位。
角度本身不是VectorArithmetic的东西
但是显然弧度的角度是Double
所以这个animableData再次
我将使用相同的技巧
获取和设置。有点棘手
因为我们必须在这里使用AnimatablePair，
但是AnimatablePair只有两个变量，第一个和第二个，
返回第一个可动画的东西
关于第二个可动画化的事情。
所以对于我们来说，我们将返回一个AnimatablePair
首先是startAngle的弧度。
第二个是endAngle的
角弧度。
那就是我们的animableData
然后设置它只是设置我们的startAngle
成为弧度为
这是AnimatablePair，即newValue，先点
和endAngle
是一个角度，弧度，
这是AnimatablePair的第二个。
所以在这里我们连接了两个变量
此动画，分段动画
这就是我们需要做的。
因为这只是意味着这个形状将会
在动画过程中反复绘制
这两件事都被动画化了
因为它们是东西被切成薄片
动画系统将其分解成小块。
这就是animatableData的全部内容。
现在，我告诉你，这个动画系统很优雅，
就是只有一个变种
作为双向双向访问的唯一入口
动画的东西。我认为设计很不错。
我不为苹果工作
因此，我认为我是独立的第三方，
我认为他们在这方面做得很好。
好吧，现在这个Pie可以动画了
现在我们的模型知道如何追踪
剩余时间。
因此，让我们采用“视图”并将这两件事放在一起。
这是我们的派，就在这里
我们想要，我要离开起点
始终笔直向上，零度，向上向上。
我要改变我的endAngle取决于
我还剩下多少时间。
让我们从一个简单的开始，即
让我们拿卡剩余的红利，
这是剩余的百分比奖金乘以360。
我要倒退，因为这个派
负面地下降到零
我最终希望将其降低到零。
看看有什么用。
好吧，我们开始吧，哦，这不是动画。
嗯，这很奇怪。
哦，但我以为我在那里看到了什么。
哦，看起来它实际上是在显示剩余时间
因为我花了差不多那张卡片
这是六秒钟，我将其设置为绕转。
所以我认为这张卡面朝上大约四秒钟
可以，但是实际上并没有为它设置动画
然后这样一看，好像一直都在
但是，如果我单击离开然后再单击返回，
哦，实际上我一直都在用光
导致该卡面朝上坐了这么长时间。
现在，我认为这只是一点点。
是的，那只是一点点。
这个刚刚出现，所以它实际上在工作
它正在对此进行调整，但不是对其进行动画处理。
那么我们该如何对其进行动画处理？
要对此进行动画处理有些挑战
因为这真正使人生气的是这个角度
从现在的位置（如此处）到零。
我告诉你动画只显示你的东西
那已经发生了。
但是当显示卡时，此时钟开始计时，
它还没有达到零。
那我该如何开始要制作的动画
当零还没有发生时，这个东西变成零吗？
那是个难题22。
所以这个陷阱22会阻止我们
使用此奖励后直接从模型中获得。
现在，如果我问模型，
奖金剩余百分比是多少？
它会告诉我它总是会做的正确答案
那是模型的工作。
因此，模型正在履行职责
但是，模型并没有不断变化。
哦，还剩4.1秒，
哦，我改变了，现在只有四秒钟，
哦，我改变了，现在还剩下3.9秒，
该模型不能做到这一点可笑。
它正在做它的工作，但它以某种方式做到了
不会导致我们的用户界面发生变化
而动画只能使变化动起来。
我们只是不能直接在模型中使用它，
我们仍然必须与模型保持同步
但是我们不能直接使用它。
所以我要动画这个角度
在这里使用我自己的小临时变量
它必须是可写的。
我将不得不将其与模型同步。
所以它将是一个@State
正如我们在幻灯片中谈到的
而且是私人的，仅供我使用
因此，var，我将其命名为我的animatedBonusRemaining。
我们将其设为度数的Double
当然必须初始化
因为所有的变量都必须初始化
甚至是@State。
所以我要用它代替奖金
直接来自模型
我将使用我的animatedBonusRemaining。
现在我必须以某种方式使它成为正确的价值观
使动画发生。
我要做的第一件事
得到它与模型同步。
这必须与模型同步。
我该怎么办？
好吧，真的，我什么时候要使其同步？
每次出现此视图时，
我希望它与模型同步。
现在，什么时候出现在屏幕上？
现在它以其容器出现在屏幕上
我们没有任何过渡
如果我们不知道什么时候发生，等等。
所以我要让它只出现在屏幕上
如果我的卡是ConsumingBonusTime。
所以这只是我模型中的变量告诉我
目前是否有卡
消耗奖金时间。
这意味着它面朝上，尚未匹配
还有一些剩余时间可能是其他原因。
我不在乎由我的模特告诉我
当前是否正在消耗骨骼时间。
如果是，则此视图将显示在屏幕上。
现在，为什么我只希望将其显示在屏幕上
当它实际上是动画时？
好吧，因为我正在使用这个动画值
剩下的奖金，好吗？
那真的，我只想这样做
当我实际上在做动画时
而且，它还允许我使用onAppear。
所以您还记得我们在幻灯片中讨论过的onAppear。
这是一个调用此关闭的函数
只要此视图出现在屏幕上。
而这正是我想要的
因为每当这个东西出现在屏幕上时，
我要重设我的奖金时间
成为模型中的内容。
所以这个视图总是会开始的
与模型同步，
然后我可以开始制作动画
但我们必须使其同步。
所以我们在这里做一些功能
另一个小私人，称它为func。
假设是startBonusTimeAnimation。
我想在这里做的第一件事就是设定
我的animationBonusRemaining等于模型中的值。
这样我就一直保持同步。
总是叫这个东西，
startBonusTimeAnimation。
每当这个Pie出现在屏幕上时，
它会与模型同步，非常重要
如果您要拥有自己的版本
至少要在模型中进行动画处理
当它第一次出现在屏幕上时使其同步。
那么，现在我该怎么办？
我的派出现在屏幕上，正在显示
剩余适当数量的奖励时间，
但现在它希望将滴答声设置为零。
所以我要照我说的去做
动画滴答声降为零
withAnimation
让我们使用线性动画。
请打零。
我只是在动画剩余的奖金
滴答作响到零。
等一下
制作动画需要多长时间？
好吧，最好剩下多少时间，
我不希望它降到零慢
或比剩余时间快。
所以我要
我动画的持续时间，
等于卡的BonusTimeRemaining。
剩下多少秒了
这是剩余的百分比
这是剩余的秒数。
就是这样，所以这真的是我需要做的。
我只剩下一点自己的奖金时间，
我同步到模型
然后立即开始向零动画。
如果派呆了那么久
我们将看到动画一直到零。
如果停止消耗奖金时间，
此视图将消失。
它可能不会完成其动画
没关系，它只会在这里消失。
现在，如果我们不浪费奖金时间，
比如说卡片是匹配的。
他们已经被配对，没有花费额外的时间。
我实际上还是要在那里派
我只是不想让它动画。
这很容易，在其他情况下，
我也要放一个馅饼。
现在，这个派，
我们不在乎它何时出现
因为我们没有动画。
它当然不能使用此animationBonusRemaining
这就是这个派的意思。
因此，让我们将其与
无论模型中说什么。
现在，我不喜欢这里重复的代码，
看到他们两个都有这种填充和不透明度
所以让我们离开这里。
相反，我们将在整个过程中使用一个组
对它应用填充和不透明度。
希望这应该涵盖这里的所有基础。
这是动画时出现的Pie，
我们与模型同步
然后开始趋向于零
但是还剩下很多时间。
如果我们不浪费奖金时间，就没有动画
那我们就做一个普通的派
奖金留在那里。
看看是否可行。
好吧，让我们看。
喔，看看这个动画
哦，甚至匹配。
这是一个很好的例子，因为
我一点击就匹配了这个
所以我没有用我的奖金时间，所以看起来不错
然后，一旦我有一场比赛，
它切换到这里使用这个派
只是告诉我我还有多少钱
当事物匹配时。
对，让我们在这里再看一个
鬼和这个家伙，让我们远离这些
这将开始并返回
看看是否还有剩余的奖金时间
当我们面朝下继续时。
哦，是的。
好的，
看看那里发生了什么事
就那么简单。
现在，这比
一些动画
但是有这样的情况并不少见
您的模型或任何数据源
可以告诉你发生了什么事，
但它并没有不断变化。
这就是为什么有时您必须创建
您可以在此处创建动画的自己的变体，
但请确保您将其与模型同步
在您这样做之前。
好，今天是动画
我们覆盖了很多领域。
我们谈到了隐式动画，
我们的筋斗表情很激动
他们有一场比赛。
我们有几个明确的动画
当我们选择一张卡时，我们在这里做了一个
当我们制作新游戏时，我们在这里又做了一个。
我们还展示了动画ViewModifiers
我们的卡片正在制作动画
我们甚至展示了如何不让View来来去去
如果我们不希望他们来来去去，
我们动画了我们的形状
我们要做的就是说
Shape内的哪些数据可以动画显示，
在我们的情况下，这是此处的起始终止角度。
我们也做了一些过渡，对，
我们进行了比例转换，以便当卡片匹配时，
他们会消失。
顺便说一下，我们可以进行类似的转换
例如，如果我们把这些饼放在这里，
.scale饼图上的过渡，
然后当我们的馅饼出现时，
放大到不错的样子
有点放大。
如果我们没有规模，我不知道你以前是否注意到，
但这实际上是一种淡入
也许我们可能想说我们不想要任何一个
我们将使用身份转换
然后这个派，不管它来来去去，
它会出现。很好，因为通常
卡片正面朝下时发生
或在两个派之间切换
如果我们匹配，则它们具有完全相同的值。
动画就是这样
希望这就是您所需要知道的
关于动画。
我的意思是，动画当然是一个强大的子系统，
我们不必在应用程序中添加很多行代码
使其做所有这些疯狂的事情。
但我并没有尽一切可能给你看
您可以通过任何方式在动画中使用。
所以还有很多东西要学
但现在让您了解基本知识。
下周，我不确定我们要做什么
下周，我们要做一些手势，
你可能知道，捏手势之类的东西
否则我们可能会做
TextFields和Pickers，我看到了这个问题
在班级论坛上，
也许我们会这样做。
我们不太确定下周要去哪里
但请继续关注，然后您会发现的，
-[旁白]欲了解更多信息，请访问stanford.edu
(gentle music)
- [Narrator] Stanford University
- [Instructor] CS193P Spring of 2020.
This is lecture six
and today I'm gonna
cover two brief topics,
either brief because they're minor topic
like property observer,
or I'm only gonna get into
so much detail in them
like @State.
And then we're gonna dive
into our main topic today,
which is animation, which
is what our demo is gonna be
all about.
So let's get started.
Property observers, only
do a quick word on this.
The main thing I want you to understand
about property observers,
it's just a way to watch a var
and see when it changes
and then take some action.
Now, a lot of times people get confused
between property observers
and computed vars.
They're completely different things,
nothing to do with each other.
Here, I have this var isFaceUp
which has a property observer on it.
That var is stored in memory,
it's not a computed var in any way.
In the property observer there
willSet I'm just watching
for when isFaceUp is gonna be set
and if the new value
it's gonna get is set,
so in other words thing is gonna face-up,
then for example, in this case,
like maybe in our Memorize game,
I'm gonna start using bonus
time, start the little pie
behind our emoji started ticking.
And if the isFaceUp is just
about to be set to false,
I'm gonna stop using the bonus time.
So the newValue in here that purple thing
that's a special var that only appears
in the will sets here.
And of course, there's a didSet
I'll use that in the demo
just to be different,
inside that one oldValue is
what the value used to be
before it changed.
Alright, for this next topic,
I want to explain something
that not obvious about what's going on
and I haven't really
talked about this before,
but your View like CardView,
and your EmojiGameView,
they're all read-only.
In other words, if you
look at the top View
and all the SwiftUI on your
device, there's a let there.
And you might think that's impossible.
How can we not be changing the Views
views are changing all the time.
But we are not, the read-only,
and that means that
having a var that stored
in our View is kinda useless.
We can't set its value anyway
the only exception is vars that are set
when you create
the View.
So like in CardView we have isFaceUp,
it's set by people who create it,
so that kind of makes
sense for that to be a var.
But anything else that's not set that way,
it might as well be a let.
Or if it's a computed var definitely
just wants to be a read-only computed var,
which is the only kind of
computed vars we've had so far.
Why?
Why are they all read-only?
Well, functional programming,
one of the awesome things about it,
is that it's very clear about mutability,
when can this be changed?
And there's a huge premium on good designs
to having things be immutable.
When things are immutable,
nobody's changing it behind the scenes
or doing something that is
messing up the provability
that your code actually works.
And also, when things
are mutable or immutable,
when they change, you know they change,
and you can do something about it.
That's how we can use
these property observers on
value types so effectively.
In the case of SwiftUI,
it wants to be knowing
when things are changing,
and when they're changing, It
wants to do the minimum amount
of work to replace the View
hierarchy with the right Views.
And in fact, that is what's happening,
if isFaceUp
changes,
it makes a new CardView that has that.
That is how this is all working.
This is actually a wonderful thing for you
you might not think so.
The fact you can't have
read-write vars is really good
because remember that your Views
are supposed to be stateless.
They're supposed to always be reflecting
what the state of the Model is.
That's where the state
is, is in the Model.
So you shouldn't need any
state of their own, right?
No need for them to be not read-only.
Well, mostly,
and not 100% true.
So let's talk about when
Views do need some state.
And there are a few rare times,
when it does need state,
it's always temporary.
Views never have any long-term storage
that's always gonna be in your Model.
This is just temporary situations
where you might need a little storage.
What are some examples of
temporary storage you might need?
Well, you might enter an "editing mode",
where you're gonna collect
some data from the user
and gather it up and then call
an Intent to change the Model
with that data you've
collected or whatever.
So just temporarily, you're collecting it.
You might have been
displaying another View,
some other View that
is collecting some data
like a TextField, or a Picker,
like we saw on that post in Piazza
or have a View that's an Alert,
you're giving the user an Alert,
you just wanna keep track
of the fact that it's up
until the user hits cancel,
then you're like, "argh it's gone."
And so you're just having a Bool,
whether that thing is up or not
that kinda really tiny
temporary data, or an animation.
Animation only reflects
things in the past.
So if you wanna have an
animation that's kinda
going along with the present,
you have to have a little
var, which is the future.
So you can set that var to the future
and animation will start
animating towards the future.
Hopefully, you're setting the future to be
the same thing that's gonna eventually be
in your permanent state.
But you're only using that var
during the time the animation is happening
and we know that animations are short,
they're little temporary things.
So animations, another case
of these temporary storage,
and we'll see doing that in the demo.
We can, in fact, create
storage in our read-only Views
and we do it by marking a var
that stores the information
we want with @State.
So @State you know,
like @Published, @ObservedObject,
it's a property wrapper.
Note that I've marked this state private.
That's because state is private to you
It's just temporary storage
you're using in your View,
nobody else is gonna be looking at it.
So by marking it private,
just kind of remind yourself,
yeah, yeah this is a little private state
temporary state right there.
And of course, the type of
this thing can be any type,
you're just declaring
a var basically here,
that's gonna be read-write.
But it can be any type that you want.
An important thing to
understand about this State var,
something temporary
here is if I change it,
my View might get redrawn.
If my View depends on something temporary,
and it changes in a way that
makes my body draw differently
it'll get redrawn.
It's the same as ObservedObject, right?
We do observed object on our ViewModel.
If the ViewModel changes in a way
that would make our View look different.
It's gonna get redrawn
same thing with state
which is kind of cool
feature of it actually.
The space for this @State var
is gonna be allocated in the heap.
It has to, it can't make
the space in your View,
your View is read-only
so it's basically making a pointer
so your View has a pointer in it
and it points into the heap.
And when your View gets rebuilt,
cause your View's getting
rebuilt all the time,
when isFaceUp changes in your CardView,
you gotta make a new CardView.
And when that happens,
this pointer gets moved to the new version
so you're still pointing at
that same thing in the heap.
So if isFaceUp changes,
your CardView is not gonna
lose its temporary storage.
Basically your temporary
storage will stay around even
as other things that are causing your View
to even be completely rebuilt
you get to keep your @State.
We're gonna learn what
these @ sign things are,
you know, @Published,
@ObservedObject, @State
they're called property wrappers.
You can read about it, in your reading.
I think it's assigned for next week.
I'm gonna explain it
eventually in lecture.
Not quite yet, though, almost there.
For now, just know that you
can mark a var with @State
and now you can write to it.
But use this sparingly and certainly never
put anything that's
not temporary in there.
All right, main topic
of the day is animation.
What is animation?
It's essentially a kind of
a smoothed out portrayal
in your UI, over a period of time,
which is configurable by the way,
of a change that has
happened in your UI already.
When the user looked at an animation,
they're seeing something
that has already changed
in the Model, okay,
or it's already changed somewhere
at the very least has
changed in an @State.
Something that's already happened,
it can't do it any other way.
Otherwise, all your variables
in your Model would have
to be constantly changing
as the animation went on
that's just untenable architecture, right?
So your Model changes,
your View changes and that change gets
animated in front of the user's eyes.
So it's showing you
their very recent past.
The point of animations is
to make the user experience
less herky-jerky, obviously,
but also to draw attention
to things change.
We wanna use the user
peripheral vision to notice
Oh, that number over there change,
oh, that View moved over here, whatever.
That is what we use animation for
and that's why we have animation.
It also just makes more pleasant,
less stressful experience
to have something
jumping on screen at you all the time.
So in SwiftUI, what can get animated?
Well, I'm gonna talk about
what can get animated
but first, I wanna make it clear
that animation only works for Views
that are in a container
that is already on screen.
So if they're in a container
that's already on screen
and a change happens to them,
what kind of change can be animated?
Well, the appearance and
disappearance of Views again
only if they're in a container
this already on screen
also changes to the arguments
of animatable ViewModifiers,
like opacity and
rotation, things like this
that boost ViewModifiers know
how to animate themselves.
And we're gonna create
one of our own today,
those changes to those
arguments can be animated.
And also the changes to arguments
are the creation of Shapes.
If you create a Shape,
with certain arguments
configured in some way,
and then you change those,
then it can be animated
to go to a new state.
So how do we kick off an animation?
By the way, that's it for changes,
there's nothing else gonna be changed
just ViewModifiers, Shapes,
and the appearance and
disappearance of Views,
wanna make that clear.
Alright, so how do we
make an animation "go"?
Well, there's two ways to do it.
One is an implicit animation
where we're going to
just mark a View and say,
whenever one of the modifiers
on this View changes,
we're going to animate that change.
So that's implicit animation
is going to automatically
every time that modifiers
on that View change,
it's going to animate it.
The second one is explicitly,
where we are going to call some
code that is going to result
in some changes to
ViewModifiers, or Shapes,
or Views are gonna be coming and going.
And we're gonna wrap that code
by calling this function withAnimation.
And inside the curly braces there,
we're gonna put the code
and that's gonna cause all
the things that would change
all those ViewModifier
arguments that change,
all the Views come and go.
They're all gonna happen together
in one concurrent animation.
So we're explicitly animating right there,
we're saying, animate
this and then we usually
do something like call an
Intent in our ViewModel.
And we know that's gonna
make a lot of changes
we want the result of that
to all be animated together.
So that's the explicit animation.
So let's talk about the
implicit animation first.
Some people call this automatic animation
essentially just declares or tags a View
so that all ViewModifier arguments
are always animated
for this View.
You get to specify how
these things happen,
like how long it takes for them to happen.
And also a curve, which I'll talk about,
you do get to control it a little bit.
You do it by calling this
function animation on any View.
So here I've called it
on opacity or rotation,
modified Text of a ghost.
I've said animation,
provided the argument there,
which is the how to do the animation,
how long and all that stuff.
And now forevermore, whenever
the scary var changes,
and thus the opacity changes,
or the upsideDown var changes there
rotation effect that's
gonna change the rotation.
Anytime those changes happen,
it's going to animate it,
because this View this
combination, things here in green,
is now implicitly animated.
That's always gonna be the
case that that happens.
Warning here, little red
word warning so pay attention
.animation on a container View
does not work how you
would generally think
you might imagine, it's just gonna animate
the whole container like one
big, somehow blob of change.
But it doesn't all of doing
animation on a container does,
it just applies that
animation to all the things
inside the container.
In other words, .animation
is not like .padding, right.
.padding puts padding
around the whole ZStack
or the whole VStack or whatever.
It's more like .font or if
you say .font on the ZStack,
all the texts in the
ZStack, get that font, okay.
Animation is more like .font
if you say animation on ZStack,
all the things inside are
gonna get that, and that's
rarely what you actually want surprising.
And so I'm just giving you a warning
that we don't usually put
.animation on container Views,
they're usually put on,
if not on leaf Views,
at least on very small,
self-contained Views.
So that animation argument
that you're passing there you
saw in the previous slide,
it was ease in and ease out, it's called,
that lets you control the
animation like its duration.
How long is this gonna take ?
Two seconds or whatever, a delay,
wait a half a second before
you start this animation.
It can repeat a certain number of times,
or even repeat forever,
do the animation to make this change,
and then just keep doing
the animation over and over.
The change, of course, has
already been made in the past,
but just keep doing the animation
sometimes you wanna do that.
And also you can set
the animation's curve.
So what is the animation curve?
This is actually determined by
what kind of animation you choose.
And the animation curve controls the rate
at which the animation plays out
in linear animation, for example,
the rate is constant
throughout the whole time
the whole animation from, you
know, one opacity to another,
or from one rotation or another
happens, linear constant rate.
Then this ease in, ease out
that I mentioned on the
previous one, it's different.
It starts out slow, slowly
changing the opacity
of the rotation and then speeds up,
and then as it's almost
there, it slows back down.
And why do you want something like that?
Well, if you're, for example,
moving a card across screen
from one place to another,
it's kind of abrupt, if it
just picks up moves over.
It's much nicer for it to
start moving slow and then
move over and then slow down
as it's arriving, kind of
like an airplane, right.
Starts on the runway stop
and it's slowly taking off
and then go in the air and
it goes to 500 miles an hour
then it gets to the destination airport,
and then slows down to
100, 150 miles an hour,
and then it lands.
So it's that kind of curve of the rate
is ease in and ease out.
You almost always want things to moving
to at least do ease in, ease out
if not the next one, which is spring.
So spring is the thing
gets to its destination
and then it kind of bounces a little bit
has a little soft landing there
overshoots the mark a
little bit and springs back
a little bit like it's
got a spring connecting it
to the destination.
And these kinds of
animation curves make the UI
a little more comfortable
for users less, you know,
jarring, less abrupt.
So let's talk about implicit animation
when I think I was just
describing an explicit animation,
which is what I'm gonna describe next.
So these automatic, implicit animations,
they're not really even the
primary way we do animation.
It probably depends on
the app a little bit
but mostly, we don't use them that much
because when you have a
kind of a group of Views,
they wanna work together to animate.
That's why putting .animation
on a container like a ZStack,
not just, we just don't do it very much.
Because if a ZStack has a whole
bunch of Views inside of it
maybe Views inside those
and this big construction,
those Views want to animate all together,
all the same duration, all the same curve,
they wanna be in sync.
Explicit animation is where we
cause an animation to happen
all with the same duration,
all with the same curve
for a whole bunch of Views.
And the way we do it is we just take this
withAnimation function, call it
with this argument, which is a closure,
Inside the closure, we're
just gonna do something
like calling Intent on our ViewModel,
that's a classic thing we do there.
And Model can change like crazy,
our View might change like crazy,
and all those crazy changes
are all gonna happen together
with this Animation that
we passed to withAnimation.
Here I'm doing two
second linear Animation.
So all of the changes are
gonna happen at a linear rate
over the course of two seconds.
Now, I'm calling a
function here withAnimation
one has two arguments, an
animation, and then a closure,
calling functions like this,
that's more of an imperative
approach to programming.
We know the SwiftUI is mostly declarative,
we just saying the state of everything
and the implicit
animations are declarative.
You're just declaring that
when these modifiers on this thing change,
you're gonna animate it.
But this is actually imperative.
Here we are telling somebody
do this and animate it
so it's imperative.
So there's not a lot of
places in SwiftUI code,
where you're doing imperative programming.
Remember, all this code
has to be in your View,
cause ViewModels don't see the View
so they can't be doing this.
This is all in your View,
it's in the spot in your SwiftUI code,
where you do imperative code
which is like onTapGesture,
Views are tapped, boom,
you're gonna do something imperative,
you're gonna say choose the
Intent, choose card or whatever.
And those are the places
on things happening
like on tap, just other gestures
we're gonna learn about next week.
That's when we're gonna
call withAnimation.
Now, explicitly animations, as I said,
are usually wrapped around
things like Intents,
a ViewModel Intent.
But you might also wrap it
around something that happens
only in the UI.
For example, that editing
mode I was talking about,
let's say you're going into editing mode
and little icons will appear
to delete things or whatever
those things want to
kind of animate smoothly
and appear on screen.
And so you might be doing
withAnimation when the user
hits the button to to say
enter edit mode or whatever.
Another imperative place
is the action of a Button.
And I'll show Buttons
today in the demo as well
and you'll see the action
of a Button is another place
we do imperative code
and where We would likely
do something like withAnimation.
This is red again, the second red thing.
First one was the red about doing
.animation on container Views.
This one is to remind you
that explicit animations
do not override implicit animations.
Implicit animations are
assumed to be on Views
they are self-contained,
they work independently,
whatever animation makes sense for them
should always make sense
to them no matter what.
So if there's a View,
and it has an implicit
animation attached to it,
then it's gonna be doing
that implicit animation
whenever its things change.
Even if there's an explicit animation
going on at the same time.
It's gonna have no effect on them.
Implicitly animations always win.
Now transitions specify
how to animate the arrival
and departure of Views.
Remember, those Views
have to be in containers
that are already on screen.
But whenever you arrives, you
want to be able to animate it
fade in or flies in from
outer space or something
you want some sort of animation
for that View arriving.
Now a transition
is only
a pair of ViewModifiers, that's all it is
one of the ViewModifiers is modifying
the View for what is supposed
to look like when it's there
and the other one is
modifying the View for what
it's supposed to look
like when it's not there.
In other words, it hasn't
arrived or it just left,
the one that's on there's
probably gonna have,
let's say it's a fade, it'll
start with the one, with
the ViewModifier, where it's
on there of opacity one,
and then the ViewModifier for
the other one is opacity zero.
And system is gonna animate
between those two ViewModifiers
to make that thing appear or disappear.
So a transition is really just a version
of changes to the
arguments of ViewModifier
cause a transition is just
this pair of modifiers.
the two modifiers can
have different arguments
and so that's it, that's all it is.
So transitioning is not really
a different kind of animation,
it's just a way of specifying
the two ViewModifiers
for when Views appear and disappear.
So how do we specify
what transition we want
the system to use when it's
animating the appearance
or disappearance of a given View?
Remember a transition
just a pair of modifiers,
so we're essentially just
gonna attach the two modifiers
we want modifier for when it's
on screen and the modifier
when it's not to a View.
And we attach this
transition using .transition,
very simple ViewModifier.
I'm gonna show you by example here,
and I'm gonna use two
built-in transitions.
One is called .scale,
that's the blue one there,
and the other is called .identity,
which is the purple one.
So a .scale transition,
its two ViewModifiers are frame modifiers.
And the off-screen one
has a frame of zero,
and the on-screen one has
a frame of like full size
whenever its normal size is.
So scale transition zooms the
View in and out from tiny,
zero size up to full size
as it goes out or in.
And the identity transition
is an interesting one,
it's ViewModifier does nothing.
So since nothing is changing
between when it's gone,
and when it's there, it
just instantly appears
and instantly disappears.
In other words, there's
no animation because
there's no differences
between the two ViewModifiers
are exactly the same
and they don't actually modify the View
so there's no animation to happen.
So bloop, it appears and disappears.
And it is occasionally the case
that when you're doing an animation,
and you have Views coming and going,
possibly you might want a View
to just bloop appear and bloop disappear
and not be animated.
That's not the default
so the default transition
is called .opacity,
which is a fade, fades in and out, right.
It's just taking the opacity
which we learned about last time,
making go from one to
zero when it goes out
and from zero to one when it goes in.
So we moderated that in that case
is the opacity ViewModifier.
Let's look at this ZStack right here,
it's basically our card kind of
simplified here.
There's only so much room on the slides,
and you can see that from my
face-up the front of my card,
I got my RoundedRectangles,
let's say don't have
them all specified there,
but you know what they are.
And I didn't put a .transition modifier
on the RoundedRectangles.
So they're gonna get
the default transition,
which is opacity. So the
RoundedRectangles on the front
are gonna fade in and
out as they come and go.
But I did put a transition on the Text
the little ghosts there.
That is going to zoom up out of nowhere
and then zoom back down to
zero size when it goes away.
That's what .scale means.
And then the RoundedRectangle on the back
I put the transition identity that means
when the back appears
it's gonna bloop appear
it's not gonna fade in or
grow out, it's bloop appear.
Now it'll bloop appear and meanwhile,
the front will be fading out
and zooming shrinking down
at the same time.
So it's not gonna be
a very nice animation.
This is kind of a kitchen
sink animation here,
you would never do it actually like this
but I just want you to understand
what all these transitions do.
By the way, you see here how isFaceUp,
which is just a conditional
inside of a ViewBuilder, right?
This is the ZStack,
we know the content
ZStack is a ViewBuilder.
And inside ViewBuilder,
it's a list of Views
but we can use if-thens to
include or not include some,
well, of course, as we include them,
they appear on screen as
we don't include them,
they disappear on screen.
And these kinds of if-thens
inside of ViewBuilders
is probably the number one way
the Views are coming and going.
So when you have
animations of the contents
of some ViewBuilder thing like the ZStack,
and it's got conditionals in there,
you wanna think about transitions,
because those things are
gonna be coming and going
and if you don't think about it,
you're gonna get fade-in and fade-out.
That's the default, but
you might want something
that looks a little better than that.
Another way that Views
come and go is for example,
in a ForEach.
So ForEach takes an Array
of identifiable things,
and makes Views for them.
Well, if that Array changes,
like new things got added to it,
or some of the identifiers got pulled out,
it's going to either add new
Views or take some of the Views
it made in the past out of there.
And those Views are gonna
be coming and going.
You're gonna see this
definitely in your homework
number three, you're gonna have your cards
somehow displayed on
screen through some ForEach
maybe inside grade or something.
And it's a different game to the memorize
the cards kind of come and
go in the game you're doing.
Whereas memorize the cards are
just really always on screen,
even when they're match
they're just hidden.
There's kind of a space for them there,
but wouldn't have to be that way.
So those are probably number
one and number two ways that
Views come and go: conditional
things inside ViewBuilders
and things like ForEach that
are conditionally essentially
building Views for you.
All right, back to the screen code.
So let's just walk through,
if we change isFaceUp from
one thing to the other,
what would happen?
So if we change isFaceUp to false,
in other words we wanna show the back,
the back would instantly appear
because we have said its
transition to be identity,
which means don't do any modifications.
So there's no animation
so it just bloop instantly appears.
The Text would shrink down to nothing,
because it's using a scale transition,
and the front RoundedRectangles
would fade out
because they have no transition
so they're getting the default opacity.
And if isFaceUp changed
to true, by the way,
the isFaceUp has to be changing here,
while an explicit
animation is in progress.
If we're not actually animating,
then these transitions
mean nothing, right.
These transitions don't do
the animation themselves
they just specify what
ViewModifiers to use,
when an animation is happening.
So if isFaceUp changes from false to true,
now the back would disappear
instantly just gone
because again, its transition
is the identity ViewModifier.
So there's no difference between
the identity ViewModifier
when it's there or not there. So it just,
it's still going off screen
though, so it disappears.
The Text would grow in from nothing
would start at zero size and
grow up to its normal size.
And the front
RoundedRectangles since again,
no transition specified,
they would fade in.
This would all be
happening simultaneously.
Now one thing to consider
about transition,
unlike animation, transition
does not get redistributed
to a container's content Views.
Remember, I told you
that we don't usually put
implicit animations on container Views,
because it just ends up
giving that animation
to each of the things inside.
Well, transition does not do that.
Transition, when you put
it on a ZStack or a VStack
it is now talking about the transition
when the entire ZStack comes on screen
or goes off screen.
So it does not distribute it
off into its things inside.
It's actually talking about the animation
of the ZStack itself
when it comes and goes.
Now Group and ForEach,
those are container Views
but since they don't put
anything on screen anywhere,
they're just essentially
grouping or creating Views
from a list of Identifiables,
they do distribute .transition
to their content View.
So if you say group and a bunch of things,
and you say .transition,
it's going to be talking about
each one of those things,
getting that transition.
This .transition function,
remember is doing nothing
more than the specifying
what the two ViewModifiers are.
Think of the word
transition there as a noun.
This is the transitions to use.
It's not a verb, like
this View transitions now,
transitions only happen
when an explicit animation
is going on.
That is the only time that
transition animations happen.
Transitions do not really
work with implicit animations.
If you try to do implicit animations,
on Views with transitions,
it's gonna get a little confused
and you can understand why this
is remember that, you know,
explicit animations are for animations
that are coordinating a
lot of different Views
that when Views are coming and going.
Implicit animations
are for self-contained,
independent working Views, that
their animations make sense.
That doesn't sound to me
like Views coming and going.
Transitions are not intended to be used
with implicit animations,
they're to be used with
explicit animations.
And that's the only time a
transition animation will happen
is when you are animating it.
Transitions are just saying
what ViewModifiers to use,
you still have to animate.
By the way, if you do
an implicit animation on
something that has a transition
and the View comes or goes,
it's gonna do some sort of animation,
but it's probably not
gonna be what you expect.
The transition API,
you know, like creating
an actual transition
is a little bit interesting.
And it's type-erased.
That means that the
actual type of transition,
which the real type of a
transition is going to have
don't cares is in there that
are the two ViewModifiers
that you're using and all that.
They can be quite complicated.
And we're trying to pass them
as arguments to .transition
we don't want that so
we want to be simple.
The argument to the .transition function
is something called an AnyTransition.
And this AnyTransition is
a type-erased transition.
Imagine, kind of like this,
that AnyTransition is just a
struct that has an initializer
that takes a don't care, kind of,
which is a transition we had
modifiers and all that stuff.
And it just knows how to do
the transition thing with it.
And what you get back
is just an AnyTransition
with no don't cares or
any of that business.
So erasing types like this,
so we simplify and lose.
We don't really lose it,
but we can't see all the details
like what kind of
ViewModifiers it's using,
we do that in Swift on a number of cases,
you can even do it with a View,
there is a View called AnyView,
and its initializer will
take any kind of View
no matter how complicated
and return you AnyView
and erase all that information,
you'll now you'll have a
View it's called an AnyView,
it's of type AnyView,
you know nothing about what's inside
or what's modified or none of that.
If you didn't understand
what I'm saying there
about type-erased, don't
worry about it too much
we're gonna see it again
later in the quarter.
But the important thing to realize is
that AnyTransition is just a struct.
It has some static vars on it
for the built in transitions
like opacity, which animates the opacity,
scale which animates the frame modifier
to make the frame go
down to zero and back up.
There's a really important
transition for your homework
called offset CGSize,
which causes a View to
move across the screen
by some offset when it comes and goes.
Alright, and in your
homework you're required
to make your cards be dealt
fly off from off the
screen to on the screen
so you're gonna be wanting
to use this offset transition
for those Views.
And you can of course
create your own transition
by just specifying the two ViewModifiers.
The modifier to use when
things are on screen
and to use when it's not, right, so
identity is when it's on and
active there is when it's not.
You can also override
the animation that's used
for a transition if you
always want a transition
to be really fast, for
example, or really slow.
You can use this .animation
that you attach to the transition, okay,
you know, attach it like a .animation.
Don't get confused by this little thing
this is not implicit animation,
implicit animation transitions,
they don't go together.
This is just a way to
override the duration
and curve and all that
of a transition animation
so that always does it this way.
Transitions can be thorny,
and a little bit frustrating
sometimes when you're first using them,
because of this restriction
that the container
that has the View has
to already be on screen.
So for example, in your
homework assignment three,
you are required to have the
cards deal out in animated
fashion onto the screen. It
can't be like Memorize where
Memorize launches and oh,
there's the cards already on-screen.
No, has to launch just momentarily blank
and then the cards fly
and automatic, you know,
kind of a deal animation
to come on the screen.
How do you get out of this conundrum of
a View that contains the cards
has to come on screen first
and then once it's on-screen,
then you can do something that
causes the cards to happen.
There's a great function in
View for helping with this
is called onAppear, very simple.
It's kind of like onTapGesture, right,
onTapGesture, when a tap
happens, it calls this closure,
executes some code, this
is kind of the same,
when a View appears on screen,
then it calls this code.
So we're gonna use this
nice little feature
on our container View.
On our container View,
we're gonna add onAppear
and in that code, we're going to change
something in our Model,
probably, that makes it
so those cards which weren't there,
when my container View first appeared,
something about them changed
now they need to be there.
Now they'll get animated coming on screen.
We're using the fact that
we know you know onAppear
that our container View
is finally on screen
to go ahead and do some Intent
to the Model that says, okay,
you can deal the Cards now.
So the Model has to change
in some way where the Cards
now are suddenly being
thrown out into the View,
cause the View is just
reflecting what's in the Model.
So if the Model says that cards are there,
when the app launches,
they're gonna be there.
So the Cards have to not be
there when the app launches,
and then after the onAppear
happens on the container,
then something happens
where the Cards are there.
So you've gotten the message,
I'm sure in all this,
that the actual animations
are done by ViewModifiers
and Shapes.
They're the things that actually animate.
How do they participate in
this whole animation system?
ViewModifiers and Shapes,
how do they get animated?
Well, essentially,
the animation system
divides up the duration
of the animation into little tiny pieces,
depending on the curve.
And then it just asks all
the shapes and ViewModifiers
that are Animatable,
here, draw this piece, draw
this, draw this piece, right,
it's just drawing them
over and over and over
and then piecing it together
into like a little movie,
which is the animation.
That's it.
That's how this thing works
it's incredibly elegant and
simple, to make it work.
The communication between
the animation system
and ViewModifiers and Shapes
is just one single var,
this var animatableData.
This animatableData is in
the Animatable protocol,
it's the only var in there.
And all you have to do is implement this.
And if you're a Shape or a ViewModifier,
you can participate in this
little piecewise animation.
The type of animatableData
is a don't care.
Actually, it's a care a little bit
because that type has to
implement the protocol
VectorArithmetic, which makes sense
because we're gonna be
taking this animatableData,
whatever it is maybe the
rotation of the angles
of the Pie thing or, you
know, something like that
we're gonna be cutting
up into little pieces
so we have to be able
to do some math on it
to cut it up into pieces
using that nice curve.
So type is almost always a Float,
either a Float or a Double
or a CGFloat lots of the time
because we're doing a lot
of drawing going on here.
But there's another struct that
implements VectorArithmetic
called AnimatablePair that's really cool.
It combines two
VectorArithmetic things into one
Animatable VectorArithmetic thing.
And of course, you can
have AnimatablePairs
of AnimatablePairs.
So you can have any number
of Animatable things.
Also, if you had your own
complicated structure,
that encapsulated animation data,
you could make it
implement VectorArithmetic,
that's just a protocol.
And it could be directly animated.
animatableData just has to be something
that can be sliced up into little pieces.
So it has to implement VectorArithmetic.
This var, as I said, is
communicating both ways
between the animation system
and the Shapes and ViewModifiers.
So the setting of this var,
that's the animation system saying,
here's a little piece, draw it,
So it's just basically
saying where in the curve,
that your a little piece
of animatable data is
during this animation.
Now the getting of the
var also matters for the
animation system to know the
start and end of animation.
Now, this animatableData by the way,
is usually a computed var
not because it has to be
it definitely doesn't have to be.
It's just that in our
code like in our Pie,
or you know, our Cardify ViewModifier,
which we're gonna modify so
that the card flips over,
it's rotated.
So in there, I really
want to call the rotation
of my flipping card "rotation",
I don't wanna call it animatableData,
it's not very good name for a var.
So a lot of times we're
gonna create a computed var
just to essentially
rename some internal var
so that the animation system can see it.
So let's get right to that demo.
We're gonna be doing so
many animation things here.
We are gonna do implicit animation,
but obviously doing explicit animation,
we're gonna do transitions
we're gonna make a
ViewModifier be modified,
we're gonna make a Shape be
modified, all that stuff,
and it's a big, long demo.
So let's dive into it right now.
Let's start our animation demo here
with some implicit animation.
Again, this is an animation
where we're going to
have some very self-contained animation
that always gonna apply no matter what.
And it's not really coordinated
with a lot of other activity
going on in the animation system.
What are we gonna do for
this is to have our emojis
be really excited and celebrate
when they get a match
by doing a somersault.
So a somersault is
essentially rotating the
emoji around.
And rotation is really easy to do
in SwiftUI, there is a ViewModifier
for it called rotation effects.
So I'm gonna go down here
to my Text, here's my emoji,
and I'm just gonna add a rotation effect
on it.
and it takes an Angle so
I'm gonna do Angle degrees.
We learned about that when we did our Pie.
I'm gonna say it if the Card isMatched,
then let's start by just
having it go upside down,
which is a 180 degree rotation,
we'll eventually have
to do a full somersault
all the way around
and run.
Click on a card, we're
looking for a match.
Oh, there it is, and it went upside down
but it didn't do any
kind of animation there.
It's just as soon as it matched bloop,
they went upside down.
So how do we animate this?
Well, assuming that I always
wanted to do a somersault
when a card matches,
all I need to do is an
implicit animation here
and say .animation.
And I just specify the
parameters of the animation.
So I'm gonna have this
animation be a linear one
and we'll have it be a duration
of, let's say, one second.
This Animation object right
here we talked about in lecture,
it's the kind of thing you
definitely would want to
look over in the developer
documentation right here,
we can see all the
different kinds of animation
easeIn, easeInOut, linear
and all these other things.
I said we could do: delay animations,
obviously create them
with certain durations.
Here's all the springs
lots and lots to learn
there about animations.
And we'll be doing quite
a few of them today.
So let's try this and
see if this just works.
Will this now make that
happen over one second,
and here's one and oh, wow,
well one of them animated
here, not both of them.
Let's try another one.
But again, it is doing that
animation over a second
to do that, but it's not
doing this other one.
Now, the fact that it's only
doing one of these is really,
there's a good reason for that
and we're gonna cover
that a little bit later.
For now let's just make
sure the one that is working
is doing what we want.
Let's have it go to let's say, 360
so all the way around.
We're trying to find a
matching pair there it is,
whoo, it's somersault all the way around.
How about these guys?
Whoo and maybe once it's
matched, we are so excited
we just want to keep going or
somersaults and somersaults.
Let's take this animation
that we have here,
this linear animation, and
let's have it repeatForever.
So it's doing the same animation
it's just now it's gonna keep going.
Now the thing is, notice
that it does do it
but then it kinda reverses itself
and then it does it again
and reverses itself.
This is really not what we want
we want to go around and around.
Luckily, repeatForever has
a an argument to it here,
which is autoreverses and
we'll say autoreverses false,
we don't want it to reverse
we just want to keep repeating
that animation over and over.
And that's because this animation returns
to where it started so it makes sense
to keep doing it over and over.
The only thing about this animation
that want to be a little
careful here about is
eventually we're gonna add a new game
that you did in your homework
and when we do that
these Views get reused.
And we don't want this
animation to be starting off
in a new game.
So essentially, whenever
the Card is not matched,
we do not want to be
doing this repeat forever.
So anytime you do a
repeat forever animation,
you wanna be careful to turn it off
when it doesn't apply anymore.
You can do that right here
just by saying card is matched.
We'll do this nice repeating forever.
But otherwise, we're gonna go back doing
whatever the default animation is.
That's kind of like don't
do this animation anymore.
Make sure that didn't break anything.
We go we got a match.
Whoo, it's working
it's working.
Now we've done this implicit animation.
Let's move on to doing
an explicit animation.
Before I do the explicit animation,
I'm going to implement
some of what you did
in your homework specifically,
I'm going to implement shuffling Cards
and also I'm gonna implement new game.
So shuffling Cards,
that's an easy one going
over to our Model over here
and when we create our Cards,
I'm just gonna say cards.shuffle.
Obviously, if you haven't
done homework one,
hopefully you're not watching this video.
But next I'm gonna do the new game thing
where we have new games
and that's in homework two.
Hopefully you've done homework two,
it was due before this lecture.
But if you haven't finished homework two,
now's the time to pause this video,
go submit your assignment
two and then come back
and resume watching this.
So cards.shuffle, that should
fix that nice one liner.
Whoo, it's shuffled now these two things
are right next to each other.
All right, well, we can still match them.
Alright, how about new game,
new game requires us to have
an Intent in our ViewModel,
just like we have the
Intent to choose a Card,
we're gonna need an Intent
to create a new game.
So I'm gonna call this resetGame
and I'm gonna reset the game
just by creating a new Model
I'm gonna say Model =
EmojiMemoryGame.createMemoryGame
to create new memory game,
and that's all I need to do.
This is clearly gonna change the Model
that's going to cause
this ObservableObject
because this Model is @Published,
all this is gonna happen and
our whole View is gonna redraw
because of that change.
So now I need a button
somewhere in my UI, right?
In my UI, I don't really
have a new game button,
I can't cause a new game to appear.
So I'm gonna add a new button
at the bottom very simple way.
I'm just gonna have my grid of Cards here
in a VStack
with
a Button.
We didn't talk about Button
and I didn't expect you in
your homework number two,
to necessarily do a Button,
you could easily have just done a Text
with onTapGesture there,
that would have been fine.
But while we're here, let's go ahead
and learn a little bit about Button.
Button is very simple
it just has an action, which
is some closure to execute
when the Button gets pressed.
And then it has this label,
which is essentially any View
you want to be the label.
So I'm gonna have the label here be a Text
that says "New Game".
And in terms of what I'm
gonna do in this action,
let's double click there.
I'm gonna do that Intent
that I just talked about.
So self.viewModel.resetgame.
Usually, when something happens in the UI,
like we tap on a Card,
or a Button is clicked,
we're gonna be doing
either Intents
or we're gonna be do some
doing something that totally
only affects the UI, just
adjust the UI in some way
it doesn't really affect
what's in our Model.
Let's see if our new game Button works.
We click here run, well, there
is our new game down there
and we click.
Let's see if it's doing anything.
We've got this there and new game.
Whoo, yeah, it did reshuffle
them put new cards out there.
All right let's see if some cards match
then it puts them back.
So our new game Button is working.
By the way, what is the difference
between using Button here
and Text with onTapGesture?
Well Button is powerful, it
knows that it's a Button.
So as it appears on different platforms,
maybe Apple TV or Apple watch or whatever,
it's gonna draw this Button in a way
that makes sense on that platform.
Whereas we do Text with onTapGesture,
it's always gonna just
look like a piece of text
that we tap on.
So we would always want
to use a Button for reals
when we are doing a Button.
We don't want to do a Text
onTapGesture solution.
One other thing I want to
mention, while we're here
is this red "New Game" String.
These Strings are red
and I'm glad they're red.
Red usually means I look
I'll watch out and indeed
you do want to watch out
when you have red Strings,
if you have red Strings
that are gonna appear
in front of the user, you need
to do a little bit of work,
which we're not gonna cover now
to make these internationalizable.
So that you can have this say,
new game in French, or Chinese or Arabic
or whatever that has to be
something that can be fixed.
And so we're not gonna talk about that,
if you're interested in that stuff,
maybe starting the
documentation by looking
at something called localizedString key.
That's a way to at least get your Strings
starting to be localized.
There's other things that
need to be localized as well
like dates and things like
that, dates appear differently.
And again, we don't have
time to talk about that.
We're talking about animation today.
I just want to give you a
heads up that that is a thing,
where we eventually are
gonna have to be careful
about the Strings we put in here.
All right, new game worked
but as we saw over here,
it did not animate right,
do this and whoo, it
just immediately changed.
There's no animation.
So we would like this
whole thing to be animated,
that turns out to be really easy to do
using an explicit animation,
we're just gonna wrap this reset
game which had a big effect
on our Model and changed all our Cards.
Well, all those changes, we can animate
with one simple line of
code here withAnimation.
And just like when we
did implicit animation,
we're gonna specify the Animation we want.
I'm gonna use easeInOut.
notice I didn't type
the full Animation dot easeInOut,
Swift we can infer that
that's the obvious argument
to withAnimation here.
And then it takes a closure,
which takes no arguments,
return no arguments,
and you can put whatever
code you want in here.
And whatever this does to
our UI, whatever it is,
it's gonna get animated.
Let's see what it looks like to do that.
Whoo, oh my, it actually did a whole bunch
of animation there, nice.
Now if we want to see
exactly what's going on here
because there's some other
stuff going on there too
some fading going on,
we can change the duration
by having an easeInOut
Animation of a duration, let's say,
two or three seconds.
I'll slow that animation way down,
which is something I
always recommend doing
when you're doing animation
is to slow things down
and see what's going on.
So here we go, let's try a new game.
Okay, see the cards fade
out, back to being face-down,
and they move to their new position.
That's what's happening
here that is the animation.
So why is that happening?
That these things are fading out,
that ghost, see he fades
out, back to his card back?
Well, that's because I told you
that transition
is by default
opacity.
And what's happening
there when we switch that
it's transitioning to a new View
and so we're just fading the new one in
and fading the old one out.
We don't really want
that, we want our cards
actually to flip over when they go
from back to front and front to back,
we'll fix that in a few minutes.
But first, let's use this same
feature of explicit animation
to make it so clicking
on the cards is animated,
cause right now it's very abrupt,
if you click on a card and
things instantly appear
so that's not good.
And exact same thing here's
where we're choosing the Cards,
from imperative code that we
can just say withAnimation,
let's go ahead and make
this be a linear Animation
and we'll make it be long as
well just so we can really
see it in action, see what's going on.
Inside we just do whatever we're gonna do,
that's gonna cause a
bunch of changes to happen
and all those changes will be animated.
Okay, so there we go to clicking
and we can see that we're
getting this fade in fade out
when we choose a card.
And notice I clicked on
this card but it animated
every change that happened including
these other cards flipping face-down.
So that when you put
this explicit animation,
it's gonna animate
everything that happened
as a result of doing what you did there.
And that includes something
like let's say there's a match
let's try and find ourselves a match here.
We're not very good at this game are we.
Let's see, oh, there's a match.
By the way, we get our
implicit animation there
and if we click on another card here,
these two cards are gonna disappear.
Let's see how they disappear
they fade out, right?
Cause that's the default transition
we haven't specified any transitions
we're getting fade-in
and fade-out transitions
all over the place here.
What if we wanted those
things disappearing
to be a little cooler animation
like how about we'll have them
shrink down and disappear?
Really easy to do again,
we're gonna go over here
to find that View, where is that View?
It's right here.
This is the View, this cardified ZStack,
and it's only there when it's face-up
or if the Card is not matched.
So once the Card is
matched and is not face-up,
this View goes away.
It transitions out, okay
disappears from the View,
and so we can just say transition here
and to pick, for example,
AnyTransition.scale.
So scale is the one that
uses frame to make things
zoom in, down to nothingness
or out from nothing.
So let's see if we can
find another match here.
Now, it's hard to do because
we have such a slow animation here,
oh, there's a match.
Okay, when we click on something else,
let's see what happens to
animate these cars disappearance.
Whoo, now notice that only
they disappear by scaling down,
but all other animations
including that implicit animation,
they kept going.
And one thing you're gonna
learn about SwiftUI is that
all animations can be
happening all at the same time
and they all just work together.
It's really, that's one of the
nicest things about SwiftUI,
is how it handles all the interactions
of animations happening at the same time.
Now in your homework, you're
gonna have cards coming
and going as well.
But you're not gonna have them scale down,
you're gonna want your card
to fly across the screen.
So they're gonna fly away
instead of the screen,
you know, shrinking down.
And when they're dealt,
when they appear on screen,
they're going to fly in, not gonna
have this nice shrinking effect.
And adding that transition
for these things coming and going,
also makes it so that when
they come back you click
on new game and they come
back, they should zoom up.
This AnyTransition and remember is
that type-erased version of transition.
So let's go look at that in
the developer documentation
really quickly here it is AnyTransition.
So here's that identity,
opacity we talked about,
which is the default, scale,
slide, slide down to the side,
down here is offset,
which is the one that
makes the View fly around,
coming in and out.
So that's probably what
you want for your homework.
Here's modifier where you
get to specify the two
ViewModifiers. This asymmetric,
by the way, allows you so
that you can have cards
come in with one animation
and then disappear with another
animation if you wanted to.
See that AnyTransition says here,
it's a type-erased transition.
That type-erasing is what makes
all this very simple right here.
It's making the return
types of these things
not be transition angle
bracket ViewModifier of
offset... it's just AnyTransition.
And again, we'll talk
more about type-erasure
later in the quarter.
For now you can kind of ignore it
and just think of the
transition as just oh transition
and not worry about all the don't cares
and other stuff that might be involved
with a non type-erased transition.
So the elephant in the
room animation here,
that we don't have, is
cards flipping over.
Really, when we have a card game,
these cards when we click on them,
you don't want them fading in like this
we want them to flip over.
That's what cards do, they flip.
So how are we gonna do
that flip animation?
Well, Swift is gonna help us a lot
because it has an Animatable ViewModifier
called a rotation 3D effect,
which rotates it just like
we rotated on a match.
If you remember, on the
match, we rotated in 2D,
essentially round and round.
We can also rotate in
3D have this View rotate
in 3D around a different axis,
this y-vertical axis instead
of kind of rotating around
the axis of that point straight out at us.
So let's do a nice 3D
rotation of this card
and just see if it works.
It's called rotation3DEffect.
And you specify how much
you want to rotate the Card.
And here, again, we're
gonna do Angle.degrees.
And if the card isFaceUp,
then let's not have it rotated just normal
but if it's face-down,
let's rotate it 180 degrees.
Let's flip it all the way over.
Now this axis, because
this is a 3D rotation,
this axis is saying around which
axis do you want to rotate,
and this is three numbers,
so for example, (0, 0, 1)
would be a 2D rotation,
cause 1, the last one here is the z-axis.
That's the one that points up
out at you from the screen,
and what we want is the y-axis instead,
the y-axis is the vertical axis,
the one that goes from
the top of your screens
straight down to the
bottom of your screen,
we want this rotation to
happen around that axis.
See what that does, it's
not gonna quite be right.
Let's see what we get here.
Whoo, wow.
So that's kind of interesting.
It's rotating,
but the Views appearing
and disappearing there
that's still happening with the fade
and that's really really not what we want.
When we first click the card,
if both the back and the front are visible
one's fading out one's fading
in, and then by the end,
the back is totally faded out
and the front has faded in.
This is close, it's close,
we're on the road to making this work,
but it's not quite right.
So there's two ways I can
think of to make this work.
One, we could have our
own custom transition,
that transition that is transitioning
between the back and the front,
where the back kind of
like we're flipping it up,
the back is showing for
a while until it gets up on its edge
and then it kind of disappears
and then when the front comes on,
it starts out on its edge and
then kind of rotates down.
We could definitely write a
ViewModifier that does that
and then make a transition out of it
or we're using this sort of
half-flip up onto its edge
to have the card come in and come out.
It's slightly more complicated really,
than I think we need to do,
because if we remember how animation works
we know that ViewModifiers
are the main things
that are doing animation.
So why don't we just take
our ViewModifier which draws
this card and make it so that
it's smart about it rotating
itself so that it only shows
the front during the first half
of animation and only shows the
back during the second half.
In other words, we're gonna
have our Cardify over here.
Here's our Cardify
when it's rotating,
we're gonna make it so
you can rotate itself.
And as it's doing it,
it's gonna coordinate what's
face-up with the rotation.
First half of the rotation,
face-up will be their second
half rotation, face-down.
Well, the first thing
we're gonna do is take this
rotation3DEffect over here
and move it into
our
modifier.
So if we put this over here,
and have this ZStack be rotated over here.
Instead of having the card rotate
in a binary sense between 0 and 180,
we want to be able to control
the entire rotation of it
because in the first half, we
only want to show the face-up
and the second half, we
only want to show face-down.
So we're gonna kind of
change our ViewModifier here,
where the main var that is
involved is the rotation.
So I'm just gonna have rotation,
I'm gonna make a be a
Double, which is gonna be
my amount of rotation in
degrees just to be simple.
And if I'm gonna track the
rotation and animate it,
then isFaceUp really just becomes
a function of the rotation
if rotation is less than 90 degrees
of my 180 degree rotation,
then the card is face-up
otherwise it's face-down
so now I've linked rotation
and the face-up face-down.
And then when I have this
rotation3DEffect instead
of having the card isFaceUp
control the rotation,
let's just do the actual rotation.
Whatever the rotation
we set this modifier to,
that's the rotation is
gonna be and it's gonna pick
the right face, front or not
face front, rotation of it,
I still want to be able to have an init
that says isFaceUp.
But now when I do that,
that's just setting my
rotation equal to zero
if it's face-up, and
180 if it's face-down,
so let's say isFaceUp question
mark zero, otherwise 180.
So I've converted my ViewModifier here
to be based on rotation,
rather than face-up
and the face-up is always
tracking the rotation
cause this isFaceUp it's
just looking at the rotation
to see if we rotated enough.
Now how do we make it so that it animates
cause this is not enough
to make it animate
if we didn't run here
and click on these things.
It's doing the flip, but it's
still doing the wrong thing
about the face-up and face-down.
When the face-up and face-down
Views come and go here,
they're still just having opacity.
And that's because this ViewModifier
is not marked as Animatable.
So SwiftUI thinks, well, this ViewModifier
does not know how to animate.
So I'm just gonna do
normal animations in here.
I'll just animate this
normally it's being switched
by the init here to one or the other.
And I'm just taking these
Views that are coming
and going because of isFaceUp
and I'm just transitioning them
with the standard
transition, which is opacity.
So we can turn a ViewModifier
though into an Animatable
modifier by changing the protocol
implements to AnimatableModifier.
So Animatable modifier
really is just ViewModifier
and Animatable, and Animatable this is,
if we looked it up,
this animatableData var,
this communication between
the animation system
and our ViewModifier or our Shape.
So we just need to implement
this animatableData
animatableData inside
here, so let's do that.
Let's put it right down
here, var animatableData.
What does our ViewModifier animate?
It animates the rotation
of our View that's what you'd animate.
So this Double is our rotation.
Now, I could use this word animatableData
here instead of rotation
but that's not very nice code
to have animatableData here.
So let's do that trick I was talking about
on the slides where I'm just gonna have
this be a computed property
and I'm gonna return my rotation
and I'm gonna set my rotation equal
to the new value of this property.
Remember, get and set, that's how we do
computed properties that are
read-write and that's it.
So I essentially just renamed
rotation to be animatableData
because this is the name
that the animation systems
is going to look for.
By the way you can't even
though this really is all
that's going on here,
you can't actually just say this
you need to say that this
is an AnimatableModifier
because this AnimatableModifier protocol
while it is just this and
ViewModifier together,
it also signals to the system,
I wanna participate I'm
gonna be ViewModifier
that wants to participate
in the animation system
so make sure that you say
colon AnimatableModifier.
Alright, let's try this.
Tap that card well, oh my gosh,
that really was amazing the easy.
See in the first half of the flip there,
when the cards face-down,
it's only showing the back
and when it's face-up,
it's only showing the front and let's try
and make a card disappear into it
so you can see the cards face back down.
Here's a match right
here and make it go away.
And notice when it went away it still work
that animation work just
fine the scaling animation.
Notice also that when we flip cards over,
there's no fade-in anymore.
These cards are not fading, the
back or front is not fading.
That's because this ViewModifier
has taken control of the animation.
And so the animation
system is no longer trying
to reach in here and do
this animation itself.
It is assumes that this
ViewModifier knows what it's doing.
Let's go back to the problem
we had from the very beginning,
which is when things match
let's find some cards
that match here.
Now I'm not very good at this game again.
Okay, I think this one. Yeah,
okay, ready, here we go match.
This one spins.
This one does not spin.
Let's investigate why does this not spin?
This doesn't spin because this
card when we touched on it,
it matched and it was
faced down at the time
we switched it to face-up.
So when it came on screen
this all this fuse right here,
it was face-up and already matched.
So no change happened,
this card isMatched was already true
so there was no need to apply any change.
Animations only animate changes.
And so there was no change
cause that View came on screen matched,
it never changed to be matched
it just was matched when it came on.
So if we want a match happening
to be animated with the somersault,
we need that card, this Text,
basically the front of the
card, needs to be on screen
when the match happens.
But that's a problem for a card,
the second card in a match
because it's face-down.
So that emoji the front of the card
it's not on screen, but we
can still have it on screen,
but hidden and that's
an another way to deal
with having Views that are
appearing and disappearing
instead of having them
actually be if-then-ed out of
existence. Instead, we can just hide them.
And the way we hide
things is with something
we already know from last time, opacity,
fully transparent is hidden
and fully opaque is
fully visible on screen.
So let's use opacity to
have the back and front
of our cards be showing or not,
instead of using if then
that makes them completely
disappear or not.
So this is a different
way of thinking about
what's going on in this ZStack.
Instead of thinking of it
as these front Views come
when it's a face-up
and then they go when it's face-down
and this one comes when it's
face-down, this goes face-up.
Instead, I'm gonna have
all four of these always
on the card.
And when it's face-down,
I'm not gonna be able to see these three.
So let's take these three,
I'm gonna even group them
to make it easier on myself.
And let's set their opacity so
that if the card is face-up,
they're fully opaque
otherwise they're fully transparent.
And this one similarly
will say its opacity
if it's face-up, it's fully transparent.
Otherwise, based off of this,
move these things around, so
they're a little easier to read
So here now, there's no ifs in here,
there are no ifs inside this ViewBuilder
Views are not coming and going anymore.
It also means that this content,
this text is always on screen
even when we're face-down,
it's just hidden.
So that means that when it
gets set to matched later,
this implicit animation will be a change
until it'll get to run.
Let's give that a try.
Here's our card, whoop,
still works perfectly there,
the front of the card was not showing
see the front of the
card is there right now
it's on the other side of this card
if you want to think of it that way,
it's hidden though, its opacity is zero.
And when I click it its
opacity is still zero
and now its opacity is one
and the back's opacity gets set to zero.
So hopefully if we find
a match here somewhere,
this guy
and this guy, they'll both be spinning
and you can see as that card
turned around it was spinning.
Let's match another one here, this one
watch the card as it's turning around
you are gonna can see its already spinning
because it was there
hidden, and it was spinning,
hidden until it now became visible.
This trick of using opacity
to make things come and go
it's really a way that you can
control whether you're doing
an animation by Views coming
and going with transitions,
or whether you're controlling
it directly on screen
using opacity.
And both of them perfectly
valid ways to go.
You can just decide whether
it makes sense or not
later in this demo, you're gonna see
that we actually are gonna take advantage
of making our little Pie come and go.
When our Pie is animating,
we want it there as an animating thing,
but we're gonna put a
different Pie out there
when it's not, there's
gonna be a huge advantage
to knowing when it's coming and going.
So it's not always the case
that you want to use opacity
sometimes you want the
Views coming and going,
it just depends whether you're
triggering things off of that
and whether you want to use transitions,
or just normal animations.
Now the last thing I'm gonna do here is,
now that we have our animation,
working pretty well for flipping cards,
and for having them disappear,
I'm going to speed them back up again
and then we're gonna go
work on the animation
of this little Pie.
So let's speed it back
up, that's easy to do.
Go back here and just make our durations,
maybe we have the default durations,
let's try the default
durations of both of these,
usually under a second
most the default durations.
See what this looks like,
mhh that might be a little quick actually,
I'm not super happy with that
I'm okay with the disappearing that fast
but when flipping the
cards I wanna slow it down
a little bit.
So I'm gonna say duration,
let's say 0.75,
see how fast that works.
Okay, it looks better to me yeah,
certainly wouldn't won't
be any slower than that
but I think that looks pretty good.
This blue would obviously be something
we wanna put down in
our drawing constants.
I'm not gonna do it right
now for time savings
but anytime you see a
blue number in there,
these blue numbers here also
we didn't do from last time
these things should all be put down here
in drawing constants, which
you have a control panel
down here to tweak and turn the dials
to make your UI look how you want.
We have this Pie
and right now the Pie is stuck
in this position right here,
but we really whenever a card flips up,
we want it to start counting down
and when it flips back down,
we stopped counting and then push back up.
It keeps counting and then flipped down
it stopped counting and then of course
when it matches, then we stopped counting
because now you've matched it.
And if it totally disappears,
you don't get as many
points as if you do it
before it disappears.
To do this, we got a couple
of things that we have to do.
One is we're gonna have to
kind of enhance our Model
to know how much bonus
time is left, and all that.
So I have actually put some code
in here that I made available to you guys
on the forum before, so
you students all have it.
If you don't have it, you
can pause this video actually
and copy it from here if you can't
get a hold of it some other way.
But what this code is
basically doing is tracking
every time the card comes up and down
or gets mapped it tracking the time used
and then it answers questions like
how much time is remaining
or what percentage of
the time is remaining
and we can learn whether we earn the bonus
and start using the bonus time
and stop using the bonus time.
By the way these functions,
I'm gonna make sure
I call these when the card
goes face-up and face-down
in my Model and also when it's matched.
So let's use those property
observers we talked about
to call those functions.
Here is my
Cards' vars.
And I'm gonna make it so that every time
isFaceUp changed here,
and I'm gonna use didSet I
showed willSet in the slides,
but I'm just being different here
and showing you didSet.
When this happens, I'm gonna say
if the isFaceUp changed to true.
So the Card went face-up,
then I'm gonna start that
bonus time running again,
start using the bonus time.
Otherwise, if the Card went face-down,
I'm gonna stop using the bonus time.
So I'm just watching this
face-up and face-down in my Card
and whenever it changes that happens.
And this is more reliable than trying to
look at all the times I
say isFaceUp true or false
and try to also call
startUsingBonusTime then
I might make a mistake and
forget it somewhere whatever.
This way, it's reliable
every time I change this
boom we start and stop the time.
And similarly for isMatched here,
when didSet, we can stop using bonus time.
If isMatched is set to false, probably
maybe we're resetting the
game or resetting the Cards,
not sure what we're doing there.
But it seems like the bonus time
shouldn't start going again.
This property observer, a
really powerful way to sync up
what's going on inside your code.
So now our Model knows
how much time is remaining
on the bonus and all that stuff.
That's what all this code I did down here.
So let's use that stuff
in our UI to show that animation.
Now for our card Pie to animate,
we have to enhance our Shape
over here to do animation.
Now shapes really already
have this Animatable,
the same protocol we
had with ViewModifier,
it's pretty much on all Shapes,
all Shapes are assumed to
be able to do animation
it's just kind of part of being a Shape.
It's so common that we
don't even have to say
comma Animatable here,
shape just assumes that
you're gonna do it.
Now if you don't put animatableData,
you won't get any animation it'll build
but usually we want it.
So what do we want to animate here
in our Cardify ViewModifier,
we animated our rotation
as we went around,
well, in our animation of the Pie,
we kind of want to animate this angle,
see this angle that goes here,
as it goes around this
angle is gonna change
the end angle here.
And if we're gonna be a good pie,
let's make it so both
angles can be animated
the starting one and the ending one.
That way we can animate either side,
depending on what we thought look nice.
So how do I animate two
things at once, essentially,
I'm gonna use that AnimatablePair,
right.
And the AnimatablePair is
gonna be a pair of Doubles,
those Doubles are gonna be my Angles here
they're in radians.
Angle itself is not a
VectorArithmetic thing
but obviously the angle in
radians is a Double so that is.
So this animatableData again,
I'm gonna use the same trick of having
the get and set. It's a little trickier
because we have to use
AnimatablePair here,
but AnimatablePair just has
two vars, first and second,
which return the first Animatable thing
on the second Animatable thing.
So for us, we're just gonna
return an AnimatablePair
and the first thing is gonna
be the startAngle's radians.
And the second one is the endAngle's,
angle radians.
That's getting our animatableData
and then setting it is
just setting our startAngle
to be an Angle whose radians are
this AnimatablePair's, which
is the newValue, dot first
and the endAngle
is an Angle, radians,
which is the AnimatablePair's second.
So here we have connected
up two of our vars
to this animation, piecewise animation
and that is it that is all we need to do.
Because it just means that
this Shape is gonna be
redrawn over and over during animation
with these two things being animated
because they're the
things are being sliced up
into little pieces by
the animation system.
That's what animatableData is all about.
Now, I told you this
animation system is elegant,
and it is, having just this one var
as being the only entry
point in both directions in
something to animate.
Pretty nice design, I think.
And I don't work for Apple
so I'm an independent
third party, in my opinion,
I think they did a good job of that.
All right, so now this Pie is animatable
and now our Model knows how to keep track
of the time remaining.
So let's take our View and
put those two things together.
So here's our Pie, right here
and we wanted, I'm gonna
leave the startAngle
always straight up, zero
degrees, up at the top.
I'm gonna vary my endAngle depending on
how much time I have remaining.
Let's start with a simple one, which is,
let's take the Card's bonus remaining,
which is the percentage bonus
remaining it has times 360.
And I'm going backwards because this Pie
is negatively going down to zero
I eventually want this to be down to zero.
See what that does.
All right, here we go
oh, it's not animating.
Huh, that's weird.
Oh, but I thought I saw something there.
Oh, look so it is actually
showing us the time remaining
because I had that card
up for about, that much,
and this is six seconds, I
set it to be to go around.
So I think that card was up
face-up for about four seconds
so it did but it didn't
actually animate it,
and then this one look, it
looks like all the time is there
but if I click away and then click back,
oh, actually I used up all the time
cause that card was
sitting face-up so long.
Now this one, I think was
only up for a little bit.
Yeah see, that was only a tiny bit.
This one just showed up,
so it's actually working
it's adjusting this, but
it's not animating it.
So how are we gonna animate it?
There's a bit of a
challenge to animate this
because what this is really
animating is this angle
going from where it is now,
like right here, around to zero.
And I told you that animation
only shows you things
that have already happened.
But when the card appears,
this clock starts going,
it hasn't gotten to zero yet.
So how do I start an
animation that's gonna have
this thing go to zero when
zero hasn't happened yet?
That's a little bit of a
conundrum a catch 22 there.
So this catch 22 is gonna prevent us
from using this bonusRemaining
directly from the Model.
Now if I ask the Model,
what's the bonus remaining percentage?
It'll tell me the right
answer it always does
that's the Model's job.
So the Model's doing its job
however, the Model is
not constantly changing.
Oh, there's 4.1 seconds left,
oh, I changed now there's
only four seconds,
oh, I changed now
there's 3.9 seconds left,
the Model can't be
doing that's ridiculous.
It's doing its job but it does it in a way
that it's not causing our UI to change
and animations only animate change.
We just can't use this
directly from the Model,
we still have to be in
sync with the Model,
but we can't use this directly.
So I'm gonna animate this angle
using my own little temporary var here
its gonna have to be writable.
I'm gonna have to sync
it up with the Model.
So it is gonna be an @State
as we talked about in the slides,
and it's private, it's just for me to use
so, var, I'm gonna call it
my animatedBonusRemaining.
We'll make it be a Double
the number of degrees
and of course it has to be initialized
because all vars have to be initialized
even the ones that are @State.
So I'm gonna use that
instead of the bonusRemaining
directly from the Model,
I'm going to use my
animatedBonusRemaining.
Now somehow I have to make
this be the right values
to cause the animation to happen.
The first thing that I have to do
is get it to be synced up with the Model.
This has to be synced up with the Model.
How am I gonna do that?
Well, really, when do I
want it to be synced up?
Every single time this
View comes on screen,
I want it to sync with the Model.
Now, when does this come on screen?
Right now it comes on
screen with its container
we don't get any transitions
if we don't know when that happens, etc.
So I'm gonna make it only be on screen
if my card isConsumingBonusTime.
So this is just a var I have
in my Model that tells me
whether a card is currently at the moment
consuming bonus time.
That means it's face-up,
it's not matched yet
there's some bonus time
remaining might be other things.
I don't care it's up
to my Model to tell me
whether bones time is
currently being consumed.
And if it is, then this
View is gonna be on screen.
Now, why do I only want
this to be on screen
when it's actually animating?
Well, because I'm using
this animated value
as the bonus remaining, okay?
That really, I only want to be doing that
when I'm actually animating
and also, it lets me use onAppear.
So you remember onAppear we
talked about in the slide.
This is a function that calls this closure
anytime this View appears on screen.
And that's exactly what I want
because every time this
thing appears on screen,
I'm gonna reset this my
bonus time remaining up here
to be what's in the Model.
So this View is always gonna start out
synced up with the Model,
then I can proceed to animate it,
but we got to get it synced up.
So let's do that in a
little function up here
another little private, call it this func.
startBonusTimeAnimation, let's say.
And the very first thing I
wanna do in here is to set
my animatedBonusRemaining
equal to what's in the Model.
So that I'm always in sync.
and always gonna call this thing,
startBonusTimeAnimation.
Every single time this
Pie comes on screen,
it's gonna sync up with
the Model, really important
if you're gonna be having
your own version of something
that's in the Model that
you want to animate at least
have it sync up when it
first comes on screen.
So now what do I need to do?
My Pie comes on screen, it's showing
the right amount of bonus time remaining,
but now it wants to animate
ticking down to zero.
So I'm gonna do exactly what I just said
animate ticking down to zero
withAnimation
let's use a linear animation.
Please tick down to zero.
I'm just animating my bonus remaining
ticking down to zero.
But wait a second,
how long is it gonna take
to do this animation?
Well, it better be however
much time is left, right,
I don't want it to tick
down to zero slower
or faster than the time remaining.
So I'm just gonna have
my animation's duration,
equal the Card's bonusTimeRemaining.
That's how many seconds are left,
this is the percentage left
and this is the number of seconds left.
That's it, so this is
really all I need to do.
I just have my own little
bonus time remaining here,
which I sync up to the Model
and then immediately start
animating towards zero.
If Pie stays around that long,
we're gonna see the animation
go all the way to zero.
If it stops consuming bonus time,
this View is gonna go away.
It won't have finished its animation maybe
but that's okay it's just
gonna disappear here.
Now, what if we're not
consuming bonus time,
like let's say the Cards are matched.
They've already been matched,
not consuming bonus time.
I actually still want pie up there,
I just don't want it to be animating.
That's easy, in the else case right here,
I'm gonna put a Pie there as well.
Now, this Pie,
we don't care when it appears
because we're not animating.
And it certainly can't use
this animatedBonusRemaining
that's what this Pie up here is about.
So let's just have it match up with
whatever it says in the Model.
Now, I don't like that
duplicated code here,
see this padding and
opacity on both of them
so let's take this out of here.
And instead, we'll use a
Group around this whole thing
to apply padding and opacity to it.
This hopefully should
cover all the bases here.
This is the Pie when it's
animating when it appears,
we sync up with the Model
and then started going towards zero with
however much time is left.
And if we're not consuming
bonus time we're not animating
then we'll just do a normal Pie
with the bonus remaining there.
See if that works.
All right, let's watch.
Whoo, look at that
animating over to this one
oh, and even matched.
This is a great example here because
this one matched as soon as I clicked it,
so I didn't use any of my
bonus time so that looks right
And then this one, as
soon as I had a match,
it switched over to
using this Pie down here
it's just showing me
how much I had remaining
when the thing matched.
Right, let's look at another one here,
ghost and this guy, let's
click away from these
and this will start and go back
and see if the bonus
time that was remaining
when we went face-down continues.
Whoo, it did.
Whoo okay,
see what's going on there, all right
simple as that.
Now, this was a little trickier to do than
some animations
but it is not uncommon to
have a situation like this
where your Model or
whatever your data source
can tell you what's going on,
but it's not constantly changing.
And that's why sometimes
you'll have to create
your own var here that
you can animate towards,
but make sure you sync
it up with the Model
before you do it.
Okay, that is it for animation today
we covered a lot of ground.
We talked about implicit animations,
where we had the somersaulting
emojis being so excited
that they had a match.
We had a couple of explicit animations
we did one right here,
when we chose a card
we did another one right
here when we did a new game.
We also showed animating ViewModifiers
we had our card here be animating,
we even showed how to not
have Views coming and going
if we didn't want them coming and going,
we animated our Shape
and all we had to do there was say
what data inside of our
Shape is animatable,
which in our case was the
starting end angle over here.
And we also did some transitions, right,
we had this scale transition
so that when cards match,
they would disappear.
By the way we could do the
similar kind of transitions
with these Pies up here
if we put, for example,
a transition on the Pie of .scale,
then when our Pie appears,
it kind of zooms in to kind of a good look
kind of zoomed in.
If we don't have scale, I don't
know if you noticed before,
but it was actually kind of fading in
and maybe we might want to
say we don't want any of that
and we're just gonna use
an identity transition
and then this Pie, when it comes and goes,
it's just gonna appear. Which
is fine because it's usually
happens when the card is face-down
or it's switching between two Pies
that have the exact same
value if we are matching.
That is it for animation,
hopefully, that's all
you'll ever need to know
about animation.
I mean, of course animation
is a powerful subsystem,
we didn't have to add very
many lines of code to our app
to make it do all these crazy things.
But I haven't shown you every possible way
you could use in animation by any means.
So there's still a lot to learn
but to let you know the basics now.
Next week, I'm not sure
exactly what we're gonna do
next week, either we're
gonna do some gestures,
possibly, you know, pinch
gestures and things like that
or we might actually do
TextFields and Pickers
and I saw that question
on the class forums about that,
and maybe we'll do that.
We're not exactly quite sure
where we're gonna go next week
but stay tuned and you'll find out then,
- [Narrator] For more, please
visit us at stanford.edu